<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-16T12:24:43+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kesem</title><subtitle>The official website of Kesem. A writer, traveler, and artist.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">13 Going On 31</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2026/02/16/13-going-on-31.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="13 Going On 31" /><published>2026-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2026-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2026/02/16/13-going-on-31</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2026/02/16/13-going-on-31.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“You teach me now how cruel you’ve been—cruel and false. Why did you despise me? Why did you betray your own heart, Cathy? I have not one word of comfort. You deserve this. You have killed yourself. Yes, you may kiss me, and cry; and wring out my kisses and tears: they’ll blight you—they’ll damn you. You loved me—then what right had you to leave me? What right—answer me—for the poor fancy you felt for Linton? Because misery and degradation, and death, and nothing that God or Satan could inflict would have parted us, you, of your own will, did it. I have not broken your heart—you have broken it; and in breaking it, you have broken mine. So much the worse for me, that I am strong. Do I want to live? What kind of living will it be when you—oh, God! would you like to live with your soul in the grave?”</p>

  <p>Emily Brontë, “Wuthering Heights”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I can’t believe I’m writing this! Let alone writing, period. It’s been a full year since my last post, where I celebrated turning thirty in my favorite place in the world. Today, I am back in Hokkaido. <br />
My website perished over the past year due to budget constraints, but now a new and improved version is slowly coming together.<br />
Just like me. I was so alive between 27-30 years old. Now, my life feels dead again.<br />
How did I get here? Why does my 31 self mirror me at 13? And what have I learned?<br />
Last year, I drew thirty conclusions. Now, I am not so sure. I already know my strengths and weaknesses. I know my potential and worth. I know what I can offer, and what needs work. <br />
Having neglected writing in the past year, I feel compelled to trace it first, and then see how I’ve matured.</p>

<h1 id="my-life-at-30">My Life at 30</h1>
<h3 id="february-2025">February 2025</h3>

<ul>
  <li>Trying to prevent my first suffocating relationship. This new guy showers me with care, and breaks the cycle of ghosting in my (unrequited) love life. But demands constant attention, monitors me to ensure that “no one steals” me, and blames me for turning him mad</li>
  <li>He suggests celebrating my birthday as friends, shows up with a cake and presents, pressures me to act like a couple, and says he wants to settle down. On VALENTINE’S DAY</li>
  <li>My best birthday, and one of my happiest days, one year ago in snowy Hokkaido, at my favorite ryokan, with my favorite hot spring and tour guide; seeing penguins and savoring my favorite sushi chain</li>
  <li>Meeting another grandma from Hokkaido who takes me under her wing (February 2026 update: she sends me presents every few months, I feel so unworthy)</li>
  <li>A Japanese aunt who exploited and stalked me in 2023 texting: “Happy birthday! Where are you?”</li>
  <li>Teaching myself music production, creating songs almost daily, and resenting my friends for ignoring my passions</li>
  <li>Returning to Japanese language school and realizing that my recent conclusion - “people won’t make time for me even if they want to because I’m not special enough” - is false. The classmate I’d been trying to befriend isn’t too busy for others</li>
  <li>Studying business Japanese and trying to socialize with other classmates, who pick phones over friendship. A creepy Israeli student from another class comes to mine every day during recess and breaking up my conversations with my classmates</li>
  <li>Giving the love bomber another chance and resisting his gaslighting until we break up</li>
  <li>Wondering why guys I dated in Taiwan still text me and whether I should have moved to Taipei</li>
  <li>Winning a prize at the school’s kanji contest</li>
  <li>Deciding that I finally want monogamy</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="march-2025">March 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Dating a famous guy who treats me to fancy places, showers me with presents, and offers to fly me to his residences. Not my first time, but still baffling, since I am used to ghosting, and feel unworthy</li>
  <li>Winning an award at a Japanese speech contest in front of a few hundred people and industry officials, but failing to 空気を読む</li>
  <li>Fainting at a clinic after the nurse can’t draw my blood</li>
  <li>My chest tightening every day because the person I’m in love with doesn’t know I exist</li>
  <li>Struggling to find this spark by dating locals</li>
  <li>Making it up to the love bomber on his birthday, exchanging sincere apologies, and achieving my first romantic closure</li>
  <li>Realizing that my relationships are asymmetrical</li>
  <li>Understanding that friendship and romance work differently in East Asia. The former is distant, while the latter is stifling. Many Asians seem to learn deep connection through Westerners, and then love bomb so as to not lose their chance to be open about their true self</li>
  <li>Turning into Charlotte from Sex and the City. “Never sleep with someone you like on the first date.” I start taking it slow, and eschew meaningless hookups. I’m still a Samantha - until romance is involved. (In retrospect, no one I date ghosts me from now on)</li>
  <li>Spending a magical week with a tourist whose country I am banned from. The only time in my life where I feel like a teenager experiencing his first romance. There is mutual love (finally!) and, even though I don’t believe in fate, signs. It’s the beginning of spring, and he’s never seen snow; the forecast predicts warm sun, when thick snow blankets Tokyo</li>
  <li>Bidding him farewell on the way to my first shift at a place that traumatized my adolescence - a synagogue. Wiping my cheeks and putting on a face at work</li>
  <li>Food poisoning from the synagogue making me so sick for a week, that I almost need an ambulance. While devastated that the tourist is gone</li>
  <li>Finding myself in yet another long-distance situationship</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="april-2025">April 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Relishing my first cherry blossoms in Tokyo, but feeling lonely since my loved ones live abroad</li>
  <li>A Taiwanese uncle twice my age arriving in Tokyo with a present for me: a duck figurine, slang for male prostitute. He showed me around Taiwan two years ago, and now comes to Tokyo to meet a “woman pen pal” he has feelings for</li>
  <li>Plucking up the courage to do something that requires a lot of confidence, only to experience my worst night of clubbing, and one of my most degrading experiences. I feel ugly, and cry myself to sleep</li>
  <li>Starting the last term in my beloved school on the next day, appreciating life as a student, and growing tired of the anti-social vibe in class</li>
  <li>Starting to chase things that scare me. If I don’t put myself out there, I will stagnate and merely exist</li>
  <li>Meeting a tourist from Europe who feels like the read deal from the first moment. Wise and goofy, mature and young, Eastern and Western, passionate and Zen</li>
  <li>Cursing distance for curtailing my best romantic and platonic connections</li>
  <li>Finding that my EU passport application is successful in proving my eligibility, yet a new language law will ruin it</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="may-2025">May 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>A rocky Golden Week, in which I perform an original song live for the first time; finally enjoy clubbing as much as my first time two years ago, when a toxic ex resurfaces to ask for tips on hooking up with Israelis (exactly one month before my pathetic plan to make it up for him on his birthday); arguing over his manipulations for hours until dawn, until he calls me a “fictional character” who makes everything up; losing the part of me that believes in romance; and, a day later, meeting a new guy (who, in hindsight, becomes my most stable, respectful, and consistent relationship)</li>
  <li>Realizing my parents and exes tend to gaslight, and re-having my ongoing nightmares from middle school</li>
  <li>Understanding the meaning of “bad romance”. I crave someone who hurts me and claims we’re just friends. I’m “on my own, kid”, but “I can do it with a broken heart”, and “I can fix him”. (Then, discovering that people don’t want to be fixed)</li>
  <li>Realizing that my life can be summed up in two words: feeling invisible. The first guy I dated seriously was the first to see me. He promised to be there for me, then hit block</li>
  <li>Breaking into tears over all this… while having sex</li>
  <li>My psoriasis coming back instead of people</li>
  <li>Finding a cure in songwriting (and steroids), shooting a music video</li>
  <li>Attending Tokyo’s most famous festivals, which pale in comparison to the countryside</li>
  <li>Falling out of love with people who show me their true face</li>
  <li>A Taiwanese guy I dated a year ago randomly texting me “I love you, I will come visit you”</li>
  <li>The Japanese grandma complaining when I don’t reply to her constant messages. “We’re like family,” she says, “and meeting you was a once-in-a-lifetime encounter”</li>
  <li>Job hunting to prevent my return to Israel, where I have to hide my true self and live a lie (this already happened in 2020 after school in England)</li>
  <li>Having my first panic attack in three years. My visa is about to expire, my money is about to run out, and I dedicate every day to making songs that all of my friends ignore. Everything I do is a failure</li>
  <li>Betraying my values and agreeing to full-time work at the synagogue</li>
  <li>Meditating at night for two weeks, embracing pain, and stabilizing my mental state</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="june-2025">June 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Dating Tokyo locals. It’s slow and steady, but the chemistry is low</li>
  <li>Wondering if requited love can be as grand as unrequited</li>
  <li>Heating up with the Golden Week guy, who calls me every day now, opens up about his secrets, and communicates candidly to ensure I don’t get hurt</li>
  <li>Dreading another ghosting, and realizing that liars have turned me suspicious</li>
  <li>One week with five exams at school, the government’s notorious Business Japanese Test, a part time job, performing live again, a Japanese work visa application, a European passport application, and volunteering at a disappointingly tame Tokyo Pride, where I see the blocking ex and club with shy locals</li>
  <li>Negotiating a contract rife with absurd clauses copy-pasted by a clueless immigration lawyer, since my boss neither read it nor wrote a word</li>
  <li>Discovering that Japanese people can be distant and artificially polite to everyone, not just Westerners, out of fear of being a burden. Lamenting this cultural pressure to be quiet, and wishing to support them</li>
  <li>Graduating! RIP my student era</li>
  <li>NOT getting paid because my boss neglects my salary, then asks me to break the visa law</li>
  <li>“My heart aches for you,” says the GW guy, “I want to take care of you.” Turns out he also fears me ghosting him</li>
  <li>Finding myself in yet another long-distance situationship</li>
  <li>Mourning my impossible romances and friends who are gone</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="july-2025">July 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>One week where I take the JLPT N2, apply for a work visa while my boss ignores my request for documents required by the immigration office, and pack for a last-minute silent retreat</li>
  <li>Worrying about my future, feeling unseen by my friends, and taking a break from social media. I fret about hurting the tourists with my absence, even though we’re just platonic at this point, but they aren’t there for me</li>
  <li>Saying goodbye to the classmate I like the most. Turns out she also wanted to make friends and disliked the anti-social vibe at school. Sad we didn’t hang out more</li>
  <li>Meditating from dawn to night while sitting still for almost two weeks at a Buddhist centre in the countryside, where talking, making eye contact, using technology, exercising, reading, and writing is forbidden. I do the latter on my first day, agonize over my disobedience, confess, almost get expelled, and abide by the rules; suffer constant pain and cramps, disagree with the brainwashing lectures, and starve from two meals per day; enjoy the digital detox and clean air, rewrite an old story, compose five songs, and draft three albums; recall why art is my ride or die, followed by health and the people I love; count the hours to freedom, but then appreciate this experience so much, that I almost extend my stay</li>
  <li>Second time where I go on a digital detox in Japan and check out with a local guy I feel tension with. Last time I was too shy to ask for his number, but this time I wait at the train station, and we hang out</li>
  <li>Returning to life in the world’s busiest hub feeling cleansed and peaceful; missing neither drama, nor humans; eager to write - only to drop my electronics into the bath</li>
  <li>Not knowing who I am anymore: an introverted writer who doesn’t need people, or an extroverted adventurer who aches for love</li>
  <li>Reuniting with a guy I dated two years ago in Korea. Neither of us thought we’d meet again</li>
  <li>Sweating every day while dying of boredom, because I can afford neither a computer nor a trip on my last days of freedom before work</li>
  <li>Fancying stand-up comedy and preparing jokes</li>
  <li>“You changed me and gave me hope,” says GW. I can help people, after all? We admit our feelings, but agree to just be friends</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="august-2025">August 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>The beginning of my worst period since 2022. With eleven hours of my weekdays going to work, commuting one hour each way on the world’s busiest train line to a company where I earn little to juggle its operations by myself as the sole employee in the office, and most of my leisure spent on planning my family’s fall visit, my social life is over</li>
  <li>Trying to take initiative at work by optimizing operations, addressing customer complaints, clarifying bewildering practices, and reducing costs, until my boss shuts it down to “double my workload” (direct quote)</li>
  <li>Discovering that my contract omitted “become the personal assistant of a family that doesn’t speak Japanese”</li>
  <li>Agonizing over hurting people with my ongoing disappearance, while feeling too drained to return to social media</li>
  <li>The creepy Israeli student cancelling his best friend (another Israeli student) because he can’t stand it when people (like me) have other friends and not give him undivided attention. He jokes that he and I should go on dates (he told me he’s aroace), shows up unannounced at my doorstep, and forces me to go to dinner with him</li>
  <li>Spending my lunch breaks with the only guy who seems to value me (GW)</li>
  <li>Doing stand-up comedy at a bar. The audience laughs!</li>
  <li>Passing the JLPT with a high score!</li>
  <li>Entering a Western portal in a Japanese beach town where people show skin, play music, and socialize. A wacky Japanese grandpa, married to an Israeli woman, calls me Kesennuma-kun and Gaza “the world’s skinniest country” (thereby dethroning Japan)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="september-2025">September 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>FINALLY GETTING PAID AND BUYING A COMPUTER</li>
  <li>No longer agonizing over unrequited love. I finally have someone who loves me and is there for me</li>
  <li>Re-planning my family’s newly-extended visit, because my boss rejected my vacation</li>
  <li>Every person who hears about this job tells me to quit, report him to the media, and escape to Israel. But I live in my favorite neighborhood of my favorite city in my favorite country, where I am free to be myself, and in my private time, to do as I want</li>
  <li>Trying crowd work at the comedy bar</li>
  <li>Incorporating more protein into my diet and finally gaining weight</li>
  <li>The love bomber messaging me as if we’re dating again</li>
  <li>Celebrating my first day off by visiting the bank and post office, since my job bars me from running errands (finally, a Japanese debit card!)</li>
  <li>Surprising my family at Narita airport and embarking on an intense three-week trip in Japan, while working half of the time at the office</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="october-2025">October 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Fighting with my mom every day on the trip because she wrinkles her nose incessantly and screams at me for creating a bad itinerary, which she never deigned to glance at in the six months it took me to plan it</li>
  <li>Getting along with my sister, enjoying Japan and our precious time together</li>
  <li>Agonizing because I love my mom but feel mistreated by her for a decade</li>
  <li>Re-visiting favorite places in Japan for the first time in 2.5 years and taking bullet trains across the country to make it to the office and then meet my family again in Kansai. I have no moment to myself</li>
  <li>Finishing the trip physically and emotionally exhausted, limping from back pain for two weeks because of physical labor outside my job description, and consulting my school for legal advice</li>
  <li>Asking my boss to work four days a week due to health reasons resulting from said work, only to be fired on the spot</li>
  <li>Confronting a close friend about her lack of support, only to enter a series of long fights late on work nights, and be blamed for her behavior</li>
  <li>The second annual Friends Visit Tokyo Between October to January For Some Reason, Stay in My One-Bedroom Apartment, and Expect to Hang Out All Day Long begins with three months of friends suddenly acting like we’re besties because we temporarily reside in the same city. I genuinely have fun with them, but it drains my meagre energy and resources</li>
  <li>Wearing a summery Halloween costume to a down-pouring, heavily-policed Shibuya</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="november-2025">November 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Freezing every day from now on as a Middle Easterner in a climate that is actually cold</li>
  <li>My boss monitoring me out of spite more than any predecessor (and I’ve never had a boss who didn’t micromanage, swindle, and exploit)</li>
  <li>My mom monitoring, screaming, controlling, and guilt-tripping me from Israel, to the point where I nearly cut ties with her at 30 years old (having done this with my dad at 15 years old), only to be contacted by the Jewish community in Tokyo asking if I’m ALIVE because I screened her angry phone calls for a few hours. She nearly contacted the embassy and police (the latter already happened in 2022)</li>
  <li>Helping the close friend who fought me in October with her crisis. She cries that no one has supported her like this, and apologizes</li>
  <li>The creepy Israeli continuing to message me just to vent about his best friend</li>
  <li>Finding out I’m fired even though we agreed on four-day workweeks. I lose my income, my visa security, and my remaining energy. I can’t even talk</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="december-2025">December 2025</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Free from hell, but at what cost?</li>
  <li>Reuniting with the close friend who is now visiting again, happy we’ve resolved our problems</li>
  <li>Sightseeing Tokyo to get some forest therapy via fall colors</li>
  <li>Being pressured into an impromptu trip to Israel because my dad suddenly won the president’s award. It’s been a year since my last visit, and every week someone tells me to come home. I am torn between using this rare opportunity of not losing money and vacation days on an undesired trip, and dreading more arguments</li>
  <li>Reuniting with GW on a weekend full of romantic tension. “Is this a mistake?” he cries during sex. “Should I move to Tokyo, or you to my city?” But we want different things, and agree to just be friends</li>
  <li>Realizing I suffer from Tourist Syndrome, where the highlights of my platonic and romantic life are far and ephemeral</li>
  <li>Chasing my boss for termination documents and being ghosted; discovering he has never insured me, and just took my money; booking a last-minute flight to Israel; rushing to unemployment agencies and the immigration office; sending documents to my workplace via express delivery with detailed instructions</li>
  <li>Reuniting with friends and family, surprising my mom, savoring my favorite food, meeting the prime minister and president in Jerusalem, and actually having a good time in Israel (I’m still shocked)</li>
  <li>Running into a Thai-Israeli girl I met three years ago in Korea. In ABU DHABI</li>
  <li>Celebrating Christmas in Japan with the close friend</li>
  <li>Returning to social media after six months, only to find that people I miss a lot didn’t notice I was gone</li>
  <li>Suffering my worst sleep problems since 2022 due to jet lag and insomnia (I used to be treated at a sleep clinic and achieved progress, but now my life is upside down again)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="january-2026">January 2026</h3>
<ul>
  <li>More unemployment agencies, since my boss lied and didn’t do his work!</li>
  <li>Trying to find a job and not being a failure!</li>
  <li>Back to rotting in bed without financial security, budget for my social life and passions, motivation, visa security, certainty about my future, success, stable support, and recollection of being in love. As if I’m a grad student again, quarantining alone in the UK while writing all day long (but hey, I finished some short stories)</li>
  <li>The final nail in the coffin being the death of my blog. (Money problems) I wrote 2,500 pages of content every day for over a year, but what was I expecting, anyone to notice?</li>
  <li>Deciding not to date until my life is stable and my issues are solved</li>
  <li>Not being in love with anyone for the first time in three years. I’m finally free</li>
  <li>Reading, watching movies, and playing video games for the first time in three years. In “Children of Emotionally Immature Parents”, a clinical psychologist describes my parents and exes word-for-word, explains red and green flags in people, and, to my surprise, recommends tactics I’ve been criticized for since high school: trying to help people; and growing apart when they refuse to grow</li>
  <li>Overhauling decade-old projects and scrapping others, because it’s time to admit that some of my stories don’t work</li>
  <li>Stabilizing my sleep</li>
  <li>Finding a better community of young and friendly Israelis in Tokyo than the old, crooked synagogue</li>
  <li>Attending Lady Gaga’s concert with another visiting friend. It’s not just my first concert like this and my biggest idol, who I’ve loved since her debut album. I see myself in her on stage, and recall how I performed for years in childhood. The next day, I can’t eat from all the inspiration</li>
  <li>Living and breathing music for a week, where I write ten songs day and night in bed. I go in a new direction creatively, until my head explodes with ideas, and I finally go for a walk</li>
  <li>Getting compliments for my music for the first time… from strangers</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="february-2026">February 2026</h3>
<ul>
  <li>Enjoying a snowy weekend in Tokyo. Until my pipe burst and washing machine broke</li>
  <li>The creepy Israeli student hosting his former best friend at his apartment, pretending that they’re on good terms, blocking her when she returns to Israel, then showing up unannounced on my doorstep with a present because “we should hang out every day”</li>
  <li>Struggling to find a job, worrying about money and visa</li>
  <li>Preparing my new website, sorting my life story and thoughts</li>
  <li>Growing tired of people who complain endlessly without taking action to solve their problems, live a lie instead of being themselves, and choose the easy way. I know how they feel and how hard it is to overcome this, but I managed to do so - why can’t they?</li>
  <li>Re-reading my 2025 journal with shock. I cried over people? I was in love? Why do things keep happening to me? Am I too trusting - or plain insufferable?</li>
  <li>Another rocky Valentine’s Day, in which the Taiwanese uncle confesses his love for me; I realize I enable clingy people by acting nice, and block him, the lover bomber, and Israeli student; perform stand-up comedy and new songs at a queer party with improved confidence and success; sleep two hours; then fly to Hokkaido</li>
  <li>Deciding to find a balance between my mental serenity after the silent retreat, and my tendency to follow the heat of the moment. Maybe it’s good none of my long-distance romances worked. It’s definitely bad when people pressure me with presents and extreme attention</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="my-life-at-13">My Life at 13</h1>
<p>As a child, I dabbled in a lot of arts.<br />
I mailed the most famous children’s author in Israel books with fan-fiction that I wrote. <br />
I created a theatre show that I performed every year from kindergarten to middle school. <br />
I played the piano for six years. <br />
I was in the school choir, and opened the graduation show with a solo. <br />
I painted every week and created costumes.<br />
Until middle school, when I was bullied and alone. I quit my hobbies, studied Japanese, and hid my thoughts and emotions. On my 14th birthday, I journaled about my growth. <br />
(The following is a translation of my diary in Hebrew - I will upload pictures of it soon)</p>

<h3 id="16-february-2009">16 February 2009</h3>

<p><em>I’m not excited at all, I just feel like it’s another normal day. Always, every year, I remember waking up with a smile on my face […] a million kids bullied me and called me gay, made impressions of me and cussed at me. I’m used to these things but the weird thing is that today it happened more than ever!</em></p>

<p>Here I mention a new Pokemon game I’d wanted for three years. In January 2026, I finally got Pokemon Scarlet, which I’d wanted for three years.</p>

<p><em>I’ll probably go out with B and A to a charity event, which sounds fun but kind of screws up my plan to come out in front of them. I think the timing is good and the opportunity as well and we’ll probably be alone (mom at home? Need to check) and the most important thing is that I feel ready, and I’ve been planning this for two weeks now. I really hope it will work out because it will finally help me a lot and reduce a bit of all my stress […]</em></p>

<p><em>I have messed-up genes and I hate my body and my appearance, and I am under so much stress that I don’t know what to do. I used to cry a lot and this year I cried only once. It began as usual when I told myself I wouldn’t cry anymore, but now I’m incapable of doing it. I think it’s because even though I’ve kept all the wounds inside, and it really made things hard for me and for years I’ve felt so emotional and sensitive and now I don’t feel that at all. I expect myself to cry now as I’m writing this, but… nothing.</em></p>

<p><em>I think it’s because somehow, with time, everything healed. The bullying only became worse but I just became stronger… and a lot more. It doesn’t get to me at all anymore, those words don’t bug me at all at all, and all the wounds, the grudge and the anger that have accumulated inside me all these years are gone. I became stronger and I’m happy for that partially. I, while writing all this, realised I’d simply developed a bulletproof shield for myself, one super strong […]</em></p>

<p><em>I don’t think it’s good – I mean, it’s good that I’ve grown up, that it doesn’t get to me anymore all those things and that I’m better than that. The fact that I’ve learned to ignore and not get hurt fills me with joy, because I know at least until the end of the school year the bullying will continue and right now it’s on the rise even though apart from today the entire year went well in that sense. But on the other hand I’m so bulletproof by now, and the “wall” I’ve developed for myself is so strong and extreme that no one has the ability to go through it. No one, and I barely share people with my secrets.</em></p>

<p><em>It’s very hard for me to open up, and I’m really scared of how people might react. There are so many who hate my kind of people, and especially you can see it in school. But I know it’s part of the routine, and it will always exist: not just homophobia, but the kids in class. They’re just confused and especially during puberty it’s hard for them to run into people like that, to understand them and know how to react. So I’m not fazed by this at all and it doesn’t get to me a-t a-l-l. Anyway I’d like – s-o badly, my emotional stress is so high even though lately it’s barely felt. I’m very confused about this situation, and I’d like to find out about this transformation within me – I don’t think it’s connected to my sexuality – it also really interests me, and of course I want to understand what happened, how it affects me. Right now I understand all the stress I’ve always felt is gone; I’ve always felt so hurt, so sensitive… it’s not only that this, and nothing else right now, bothers me, but that I’m not even crying. I think it stems from me maturing emotionally in a very extreme way, but also because I’ve just completely shut myself. I’m not open at all.</em></p>

<p><em>And the thing is I’m d=y=i=n=g for a hug, for touch, for warmth and love, and a boyfriend. I feel really desperate, I’m ready for a boyfriend but I understand it’s really really not simple. It will happen with time… I’m sure. :P</em></p>

<p><em>And now it’s all coming back to me. Just as I’m writing all this. I’m also beginning to formulate a certain theory about my behaviour. I also think after what happened this year: my heart-to-heart conversations with H, and her decision to cut ties with me, really hurt me even though I know it was entirely my fault. I know I hurt her, a lot, and she even told me it was irreparable damage. And she asked me to cut ties. And it made me sad as hell because I really love her [platonically] and it’s important for me to stay on good terms with her. I understood her and therefore did as she asked. But I was sad.</em></p>

<p><em>It also hurt my relationship with B. And suddenly we began to talk, and she also told me the situation didn’t make her happy. And now I’m happy like I don’t know what… the relationship has gotten so great. We’re closer than ever. I’m in the best relationship with the girls, all of them […]</em></p>

<p><em>Anyway, things are completely fixed. And the thing is I think because I felt so relieved due to the good relationships now, and so happy with the situation, that I just didn’t address my serious problems because I was so happy and thrilled. I guess I just pushed them aside. They’re probably buried, deep deep inside me, and starting to erupt right now, as I’m writing, and remembering it all […]</em></p>

<p><em>I planned to come out of the closet in front of them [B and A] but I was counting on an empty house, and it ruined my plan. I escorted them out and when we said goodbye I thought about telling them, but I thought it’d be too forced, irrelevant and the location was bad. So I gave up.</em></p>

<p><em>I do feel ready, very, and I now begin to feel again the great need in emotional discharge, but I realised it won’t happen. I do want it to be at the “right time” – I don’t just wait and wait for nothing, because I know there’s no such thing and that you need to initiate on your own. But today I realised it won’t happen. I wanted to take advantage of this special day, but I felt it was forced, urgent and just inappropriate. Today was too cramped and I didn’t get enough privacy – only now I finally have some time to breathe, and barely too. I haven’t eaten dinner yet (21:00), and I also need to finish the manga that Ziv from Japanese lent me and return it to him tomorrow because I’ve had it for a month already. And I’m really tired, I’m falling asleep as I’m writing this. But it’s important for me to write all this. I guess the real recreation on my birthday is mental and emotional discharge to my diary, writing and organizing my thoughts and emotions, which I think is a very important thing, especially in my predicament and need.</em></p>

<p><em>Besides I’m not excited at all on this day, and I thought about it and I think it’s not for nothing: everything is connected to everything, and even in this matter. When I shut myself down emotionally over the last few months I grew up A LOT. A LOT. So, while all these last years I was just radiant, over the moon – I couldn’t take the smile off my face on my birthdays – this year I’m not. And it also shows my maturation. Not the physical one, which unfortunately came many years too soon, but emotional maturation. And I’m happy for that and thrilled, and very proud of myself, and I think it was the best present I could’ve asked for my birthday. I finish this diary, which I love so so much, with my favourite characters and series – Happy Potter, which will forever be a part of my life – with official maturation, wisdom, deep knowledge, and most importantly a lot of order within me. All this writing made me organise my thoughts and understand things better, and I’m sorry I didn’t write all this time in the diary because I’m SURE! it would’ve helped me a long time ago, and I could’ve saved myself great sorrow, but the important thing is that it’s here! I plan in the very near future to tell B, I don’t know who else right now, about me being gay, and even more about myself that is no less important. I will start with a journey to find my self, and of course a new diary! So, to be continued. 😊</em></p>

<h1 id="my-life-at-31">My Life at 31</h1>

<p>Everything about my existence is summed up in the above diary entry. I’ve always felt like an outsider, a stranger to my species; an alien in a world of monsters.<br />
It’s taken me years to emerge from my spacesuit. At 30, I was finally on stage again. I’d focused on writing for fifteen years, but by 31, found myself exploring multiple mediums: prose, poetry, music, and comedy. <br />
Since last winter, I wrote fifty songs, and progressed from basic, off-key piano notes to multilayered productions. I don’t know what I’m doing, and none of it sounds professional - but isn’t that part of the road?</p>

<h3 id="16-february-2026">16 February 2026</h3>

<p>Like I wrote one year ago, there are so many things I wish to pursue, but cannot. I am confident in my abilities and vision, yet even the people closest to me dismiss my writing as poor. <br />
Humans can thrive together. The idea that there is a limited number of success in the world is capitalist to a fault.<br />
Arrogance is loving yourself more than others.<br />
Insecurity is loving yourself less than others. <br />
Confidence is loving yourself and others. <br />
Delusion is loving yourself despite not knowing who you are. You deny your weaknesses, and repress your actions. It is so freeing to encounter someone authentically their own: so you shower them with love, to prevent abandonment; and hatred, when they don’t feed your ego.<br />
This is okay.<br />
Things happen. Everything is forgivable, as long as you admit fault and change course. <br />
Which is why there is nothing more detrimental than someone who never apologizes.<br />
None of us identify as a monster. Most of our offenses are unconscious. As a child, I pestered my classmates in a desperate attempt to have friends, only to end up in middle school alone. This pushed me to become considerate and thoughtful.<br />
Now, I am better. I take criticism, make sacrifices, and weather storms. But I am still sensitive to people who are callous.<br />
I shudder to think that I also hurt others. <br />
Perhaps I make mistakes as much as the next person. But at least I try to correct them. When you call out abuse and the perpetrator denies, projects, and distorts - well, they don’t care about inflicting pain anymore. <br />
And I will never, ever, EVER! understand that. Family, friends, employers, exes: how can I make them see others - and themselves? <br />
Humans can be humane. They simply don’t want to. I can’t change someone who doesn’t want to change; the only solution is to let go. <br />
I’m not adept at this. But I think that one mustn’t excel at letting go. If you really care about something, it will always be in your thoughts.<br />
It’s such a bitter blow, learning that someone already let go. <br />
I still dream about people I love. I still have nightmares about people I loathe. <br />
As for those I love AND loathe… <br />
Once they show you their true colors, you’re stuck with what they do, while recalling what they can do. <br />
I would stay off social media, which exacerbates this tension, but artists must build a platform in today’s digital world. <br />
Messaging can be so distant, compared to hearing someone’s voice. <br />
Alienation permeates the world. But enough complaining about it nonstop. I want to be fun and funny; I will never be as young as I am in any given moment.<br />
And I’m grateful for the callous people. They taught me what mistakes to avoid. Now, it’s up to me to discover what else is out there, through mistakes of my own. <br />
I am young at heart, and my body feels strong. I’m so lucky to be alive and intact. Age is just a number, so take nudes and leaps of faith. Text your crush!<br />
At various points in my life, I’ve lost lovers and friends, all my money, health, sanity, support, success, possessions, reputation, confidence, appearance, dreams, and joy. So I don’t have anything to lose anymore.<br />
Apart from hope.<br />
Nine years ago, I wrote thesis after thesis in university about how art can save us. Even when I create to a void, I feel it healing my soul.<br />
And I know, just KNOW, that I have what it takes to spread the cure. There’s nothing I want to do more than to show people that hope isn’t dangerous. Life can be wonderful! A wild ride, full of highs and lows. We can be ourselves and find happiness, if we just SEE each other. <br />
It’s so inspiring, living in a cruel world.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fmC6b6_ovZY" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="a-resident-of-japan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“You teach me now how cruel you’ve been—cruel and false. Why did you despise me? Why did you betray your own heart, Cathy? I have not one word of comfort. You deserve this. You have killed yourself. Yes, you may kiss me, and cry; and wring out my kisses and tears: they’ll blight you—they’ll damn you. You loved me—then what right had you to leave me? What right—answer me—for the poor fancy you felt for Linton? Because misery and degradation, and death, and nothing that God or Satan could inflict would have parted us, you, of your own will, did it. I have not broken your heart—you have broken it; and in breaking it, you have broken mine. So much the worse for me, that I am strong. Do I want to live? What kind of living will it be when you—oh, God! would you like to live with your soul in the grave?” Emily Brontë, “Wuthering Heights”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thirty Thoughts for Turning Thirty</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2025/02/16/thirty-thoughts-for-turning-thirty-%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E6%AD%B3%E3%81%AB%E3%81%AA%E3%82%8B%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E3%81%AE%E6%80%9D%E3%81%84.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thirty Thoughts for Turning Thirty" /><published>2025-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2025-02-16T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2025/02/16/thirty-thoughts-for-turning-thirty-%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E6%AD%B3%E3%81%AB%E3%81%AA%E3%82%8B%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E3%81%AE%E6%80%9D%E3%81%84</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2025/02/16/thirty-thoughts-for-turning-thirty-%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E6%AD%B3%E3%81%AB%E3%81%AA%E3%82%8B%E3%81%9F%E3%82%81%E3%81%AE%E4%B8%89%E5%8D%81%E3%81%AE%E6%80%9D%E3%81%84.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“We grow neither better nor worse as we get old, but more like ourselves.”</p>

  <p>May Lamberton Becker</p>
</blockquote>

<p>When I was in middle school, I used to joke that I’d rather die than make it to thirty.</p>

<p>I wasn’t really joking. Yet here I am.</p>

<p>Specifically, in the highest ryokan in Hokkaido, where I <a href="/japan-one/2023/02/16/birthday-boy-%E8%AA%95%E7%94%9F%E6%97%A5.html" title="Birthday Boy / 誕生日">celebrated my best birthday two years ago</a>. My favorite prefecture in Japan, on my favorite season, featuring my favorite onsen, favorite food, favorite hiking guide, and memories of that surprise TV interview: it felt apt to recreate these now, and achieve closure.</p>

<p>Over the past two years, I went through more experiences than in the previous twenty-eight years combined. <a href="/about-me/2024/04/09/lessons-from-a-one-year-trip-%E4%B8%80%E5%B9%B4%E9%96%93%E3%81%AE%E6%97%85%E3%81%8B%E3%82%89%E3%81%AE%E6%95%99%E8%A8%93-1%EB%85%84%EA%B0%84%EC%9D%98-%EC%97%AC%ED%96%89%EC%9C%BC%EB%A1%9C%EB%B6%80.html" title="Lessons From a One-Year Trip / 一年間の旅からの教訓 / 1년간의 여행으로부터의 교훈 / 一年旅行的教訓">Discoveries, adventures, love, pain, life-threatening terrors; screaming in freedom, and crying myself to sleep; feeling alive for the first time, and wanting to die</a>. I’m a different person now.</p>

<p>There are many things I wish to say about those <a href="/about-me/2024/06/22/the-story-of-this-blog-%E3%81%93%E3%81%AE%E3%83%96%E3%83%AD%E3%82%B0%E3%81%AE%E7%89%A9%E8%AA%9E.html" title="The Story of This Blog / このブログの物語">fourteen months of travelling in East Asia</a>, <a href="/israel/2024/06/30/israel-synopsis-%D7%99%D7%A9%D7%A8%D7%90%D7%9C-%D7%AA%D7%A7%D7%A6%D7%99%D7%A8.html" title="Israel, Synopsis / ישראל, תקציר">three months of rest in Israel</a>, and <a href="/a-resident-of-japan/2024/06/30/a-resident-of-japan-%E6%97%A5%E6%9C%AC%E3%81%AE%E5%9C%A8%E7%95%99%E8%80%85.html" title="A Resident of Japan / 日本の在留者">seven months of studying in Tokyo</a>. But I can’t just write them all down. I have too many pursuits, and not enough free time. Adulthood sucks.</p>

<p>So instead, my new blog, <a href="/journals/sex-and-the-biggest-city/" title="Sex and the Biggest City / セックス・アンド・ザ・ビゲスト・シティ">Sex and the Biggest City</a>, has become my way of making sense of this period. I will continue to write new chapters, until the story can be published as a memoir.</p>

<p>To my surprise, school has also prompted me to reflect on my past. In the last few weeks, I had to write a user manual about myself in third person; and create a chart about my happiness throughout my life.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769359546/website_images/2025/01/IMG_0063-1024x671.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>As I look back on thirty years of existence, I look forward to a new decade, where things will continue, for better or worse, to surprise me.</p>

<p>For now, the following meditations from the past seven months will encapsulate these.</p>

<ol>
  <li>
    <p>I used to think that people will make time for me if they want me in their life. Now I know they won’t make time for me even if they enjoy my company. I am not special enough.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I crave stability, yet reject stagnation. My goal in life is to never sink into a comfort zone and unchanging conditions. I will always seek ways to challenge myself, even at the risk of losing my social, romantic, and mental well-being. Which happened when most aspects of my life - family, friends, romance, money, work, health - deteriorated throughout October, until hitting a new low in December. At least school is okay.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I love being new to things. The downside is making mistakes out of inexperience. The upside is learning from them and improving my psyche.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>My mission to experience everything the world has to offer is a direct result of my writer’s mindset. I seek pain as much as pleasure, because it exposes me to the full array of the human condition. I will say yes to almost anything.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I avoid boredom like fire. Never make small talk with me or expect me to give up my passions for safe monotony.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I can tell if I will get along with someone from the first moment. It all comes down to the spark in their eye. I know who I want to befriend or date before they even open their mouth. Some people seem so dead-eyed, abnormally normal, empty on the inside. Bollas’s normotic illness is the pernicious epidemic of the postmodern age. Every person I’ve ever loved, whether platonically or romantically, was love at first sight.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>My inability to read some people will never cease to frustrate me. I can see things from another person’s perspective, thereby understanding their thoughts and emotions. Yet some people throw me off so much, that I feel like a failure, both as a human being and a writer. How am I to create diverse characters, or stay on good terms with people who act without emotion or reason?</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I recently discovered that I have a type, much to my surprise. Sadly, it is the rarest combination of body and spirit. I can’t say it to just about anyone, because it will affect their attitude, until they lose precisely the quality that I like.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It is easier for me to make friends as an adult than it was as a child. Most people might attest to the opposite. Thus, I still struggle to make real friends. After trying to do so in Tokyo for seven months, I can’t say that I have a single close friend here. My best friends for life disappeared for no reason, while my new classmates repeatedly turned me down.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>It is not hard to stay in touch. My generation simply lacks the social aplomb to call or message. I don’t know why a quick “how are you?” is expecting too much. If you ask about my well-being, I will cherish you for life.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Humans are born with the ability to lead a caring lifestyle. Our biology does not gravitate toward indifference, estrangment, and antagonism. On the contrary, the brain is designed to seek patterns, build connections, and empathize. Society simply corrupts us into playing games with each other, ignoring other people’s feelings, and trampling peers in imaginary contests. A species whose survival depends on empathy has lost interest in mere sympathy. Thus, Hegel’s master-slave dialectics are a result of Althusser’s interpellation.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I despise human beings with all my might. Yet without their recognition, I would lose my mind. I will never stop believing in their potential to do good. Ergo, I will always end up disappointed by their misconduct.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Love and traveling make me feel alive. Yet I would give them up in an instant to publish my stories and make a living as an author. Writing will always be number one.Would I still be happy in this scenario, though, as a successful, albeit lonely, writer? I honestly can’t tell. But I will never be happy as a failed writer who has friends.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Nothing on this planet scares me anymore, and there’s nothing I can’t do, as long as it is only up to me. I can live alone on the other side of the globe and travel by myself to countries I know nothing about. I can dance alone in nightclubs and hit on people out of my league. I can control my anxiety and act despite my qualms. I can take criticism, combat any problem, and implement any desire. Every skill necessary for self-sufficiency and survival, I have acquired. My only obstacles are money, and other people’s apathy.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There is no correlation between maturity and success. Many people I know in high-ranking or well-paying positions are emotionally crippled, too lazy or anxious to perform simple tasks, lack basic communication skills, can’t maintain a household or spend time alone, are intimidated by planning and preparation, and only do as they please, instead of meeting people halfway.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The key to dealing with mixed signals is to disregard words and only pay attention to actions. I never say something I don’t mean, and consider words sacred, so it took me this long to understand that many people contradict this. If their actions speak different, there is no point in holding on to lies masquerading as promises.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I am alone in the world, whether I live in my birth country or on the other side of the planet. Because I’m the black sheep of my family - the only one with a different personality, worldview, and passions, who wants to stop arguing. They will never solve their problems, let alone admit them, and instead continue fighting over the same things for decades. They watch each other like hawks and shove their noses to every affair; criticize and scream about things they pretended not to mind; make promises or denunciations they don’t mean; deny shouting and offending; play the victim; and shift all the blame. After hours or days of screaming, during which they fling all their unrelated anger and frustration with their own life, they cry, promise to end this cycle, and then do it again. This, on top of the fact that they don’t like who I am or care about my happiness, if it deviates from their standards. I never came out of my shell and experienced joy until I left Israel, because I’d always felt judged and stifled around my family; a delusional freak who ought to be straightened. My entire life, I have let their short temper and destructive defense mechanisms slide. But they will never grow up. The truth is, I lose the will to live every time I return to Israel. Yet I’m trapped in this dynamic, because I’m financially dependent on my family. Without intending to, I have come to lead a double life, under a different name, when I’m far.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>If someone had asked me before my birth, “Do you want to come into this world, to this specific time, place, species, and family that you are stuck with?” I would have said no. This reality is not worth existing.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Then again, misery and lack are the parents of creativity. Without my lifelong letdowns, I would not be who I am.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>People can change. They simply don’t want to.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>From high school to the end of my twenties, I felt sixteen. Now, I actually feel like I’m six. “People don’t change - they revert,” a friend told me in autumn. “They build an armor for themselves in adolescence. Some muster up the courage to shed it in adulthood, and regain their original personality from childhood.” I am finally who I was before society scarred me: a bold, passionate, lonely, and misunderstood child, who is still learning about the world, leading a messy life, and dreaming of a better future. Except now, I’m also independent and emotionally capable. My political views have always been left-wing anarchist, and I rebel against any system that oppresses me.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Age is just a number. When I was 19, my best friend was 32; I led the lifestyle of a thirty-something office worker. It was always abundantly clear to me that I would go through the stages of life in reverse. Nowadays, I act like a college graduate.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>My entire life has been a search for depth. In the meaning of my existence, the nature of my friendships, and value of my endeavors. In a post-modern digital society ruled by late-stage capitalism, however, five-minute friends, hookups, and memes have turned any earnest pursuit into laughing stock.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Critical thinking is the sole indicator of intellectual intelligence. The ability to step out of your comfort zone and face the unknown is the sole indicator of maturity, which is fed by emotional intelligence. Some people are smart, albeit immature; others are mature, albeit stupid. Many are neither. I look for those who are both.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>When I come on terms with one of my flaws, I strive to outgrow it. The next immaturity I should address is my tendency to let people I love walk all over me. Whether friends, certain family members, or lovers - when I turn a blind eye to their red flags, or make excuses for their behavior, I bend over backwards, afraid to lose them. As the only gentle member of my family, I feel bad if I mistreat them the way they mistreat me. So they try to get away with everything around me. Likewise, I tend to idolize a new person I fall in love with, and let them play with me just for a chance to see them again. So I should learn how to love without becoming a doormat.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>The universe is as terrifying as it is wondrous. I love it so much, that I hate my love for it. It trapped us on a planet in a cold vacuum with no heartbeat that will expand for eternity. It trapped me in a decaying body, doomed to agonize over my mortality, before turning to dust. I am petrified of demise, whether the universe’s or mine. I am so scared of dying, that I want to die. And I am alone in the world, but so are we. Aliens are already here - there is no need to send a life signal to outer space. As the Earth warms, humanity turns frigid. Will this bizarre species ever stop prioritizing money over each other? Even my friends and family turn their backs on me. I will forever be an outsider. Humanity is where hope goes to die.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Love is the only cure for time. The only time when time doesn’t exist. And nothing scares me more than the passage of time. Wrinkles horrify me. Changing digits today makes me want to cry. What will my life look like at forty? Fifty? As a shriveled, failed writer? Who from my present will remain in my future, and what will our habitat look like? I will lose the game of life over and over again, until I won’t recognize myself in the mirror. In the blink of an eye, everything and everyone that I love will be gone. I am a speck of dust on an ancient, fading mosaic. But I’d choose terror over despair until my last breath.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I know what it means to love, but not to be loved, and thus, make love. The highlights of my dating life have all enacted the same cycle:- Someone hits on me at least on two different occasions, and suggests meeting.- I am not excited at first, delay our meeting because I’m busy, but try to keep an open mind.- We meet spontaneously. I fall head over heels. We decide to meet again.- They ghost me. Now I’m the one chasing them.- Weeks or months pass. I realize I’m in love. Yet they’ve already disappeared from my life.- More months pass. We talk again briefly. Their lack of interest proves that my feelings are unrequited.This cycle makes me wonder: am I the problem? Making up stories in my head is my favorite thing to do with my consciousness. Maybe I’m a bit delusional sometimes.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I will never be able to achieve everything I dream of, because my time on this Earth is too brief. There are a thousand things I could have accomplished by now, if it weren’t for capitalism: novels, short stories, poems, screenplays, movies, songs, albums, travels, paintings, memoirs, and more.Time is money in this world. This limitation led me to stop consuming media two years ago. I barely have time to write my own stories, let alone read or watch other people’s creations.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Physically, psychologically, socially, and romantically, I am doing better than ever. I might not have a relationship, a publishing deal, readership, someone who cares about my art, and more than one or two real friends, who live on other continents. But I am finally capable of pursuing whatever I want, while forming healthy relationships. I’ve always known who I am and what I want out of life. I’ve always known that I was different from 99% of humans, and wasn’t meant to come into this world. I’ve always had a plan, and stood behind every big decision I’ve made. It was lack of confidence, caused by my Israeli upbringing, that is to blame for my late blooming. Still, financially, I’ve never been worse. Without intending to, I have become a starving artist. I am not satisfied with most aspects of my existence, and have too many dreams that keep me up at night. Yet I have grown to love myself now, more than ever.</p>
  </li>
</ol>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dOs2kjPmAxQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="a-resident-of-japan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“We grow neither better nor worse as we get old, but more like ourselves.” May Lamberton Becker]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 3: Gotta Shag ‘Em All!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/12/15/chapter-3-gotta-shag-em-all-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0-%E3%82%B2%E3%82%A4%E3%82%B2%E3%83%83%E3%83%88%E3%81%A0%E3%81%9C%E3%83%BC.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 3: Gotta Shag ‘Em All!" /><published>2024-12-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/12/15/chapter-3-gotta-shag-em-all-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0%E3%83%BB%E3%82%B2%E3%82%A4%E3%82%B2%E3%83%83%E3%83%88%E3%81%A0%E3%81%9C%E3%83%BC%EF%BC%81</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/12/15/chapter-3-gotta-shag-em-all-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0-%E3%82%B2%E3%82%A4%E3%82%B2%E3%83%83%E3%83%88%E3%81%A0%E3%81%9C%E3%83%BC.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“You see that buddy over there? I fucked him. See that buddy over there? I fucked him too. I never thought I’d see them again.”</p>

  <p>Sex and the City (season 1, episode 3)</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="everything-is-the-opposite-in-japan">Everything is the Opposite in Japan</h2>

<p>Never underestimate the sexual contents of the homosexual brain. Even when dying of heat and jet lag, studying Japanese at school, and being swamped with relocation errands, it would drift to rainbow-filled pastures from its past.</p>

<p><em>Kissing Ryder,</em> Ben reminisced in class.</p>

<p><em>Cuddling Ryder.</em></p>

<p><em>Feeling his bare ass.</em></p>

<p>No amount of homework or difficult words could distract him from bygone pansies, even when surrounded by classmates who struck his fancy.</p>

<p>Sandro’s sand-coloured hair, ocean eyes, sharp bone structure, and Received Pronunciation made Ben stifle his sighs. Shin’s short shorts revealed thin, tanned legs. When Ben got paired with the latter, he surprised him by speaking Korean.</p>

<p>Meeting a Korean as delicate as Shin, who had grown up abroad and was fluent in English, was like encountering a unicorn. Yet it was Nathan, a German software engineer, who captured Ben’s attention the most. His eloquent speech and nerdy passion turned a simple explanation of non-ionizing radiation from cell phones into fascinating lore. Ben stared into Nathan’s large, blue eyes, and felt right at home.</p>

<p>Still, Nathan worked evenings, and barely had free time. When recess gave the opportunity to mingle, Ben’s classmates spent it on their desk, glued to their phones.</p>

<p>He grumbled in the hallway. Was it that hard to exchange a few words?</p>

<p>When the teacher asked the students to read a passage out loud, they muttered. Shin spoke so softly, that it sounded like a high-pitched whisper.</p>

<p>Nathan was the only one who talked with enthusiasm and exhibited a sense of humour. The rest seemed serious to the point of being dull. Ben felt silly making jokes in class and reading the written material in a loud voice.</p>

<p><em>Maybe I should tone myself down.</em></p>

<p>He struck up a conversation with Zelda about apartments while munching on chocolate and walnut bread. She lived in a new, foreigner-friendly flat in Ebisu three times Ben’s budget. Her social nicety seemed genuine enough to make him try to befriend her.</p>

<p>In the afternoon, a new real estate agency rejected him off the bat.</p>

<p>“Foreigners cook smelly curry,” the agent explained in Japanese. “It bothers the neighbours.”</p>

<p>“I’m not Indian,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“They throw a lot of parties,” the agent said.</p>

<p>“I’m a student looking for a small apartment.”</p>

<p>“It would be hard to convince landlords to trust a foreigner.”</p>

<p>Ben smiled through his anger. When Nathan had looked for a large apartment with his Japanese ex-girlfriend and begged to pay upfront two years of rent, the landlord had spurned him.</p>

<p><em>Was this how black people felt in the US? Asians in the West, or Arabs in Israel?</em></p>

<p>All his life, Ben had been rejected for his individual characteristics, such as personality or appearance. Now, automatic noes were thwarting his efforts, due to an attribute he had no control over. His nature could evolve, but his ethnicity was forever. He’d never emphasised it in his identity – never prided himself over his Ashkenazi Jewish heritage – and now, it was foiling him.</p>

<p><em>This was my grandparents’ past in Europe. And the present of Jews all over the world, ever since the new war.</em></p>

<p>Everyone at school lived in foreigner-friendly share houses or apartments 45-minutes away. Their location was far and their rent was overpriced, because they had turned to English-speaking realtors.</p>

<p>Refusing to settle on these two conditions, Ben was determined to find a cheap apartment in Shinjuku, where even Japanese people struggled to get their hands on one. Every agent and classmate who heard this desire laughed.</p>

<p>Yet he continued to visit Japanese-only agencies, learning real estate vocabulary instead of words used in class. He had three weeks left in his share house.</p>

<p>Then there were the move-in fees. In Japan, one didn’t pay just rent: landlords also threw in expenses at the beginning and end of the rental period. Cleaning, lock change, deposit, fire insurance; guarantor, brokerage, and management fees. Worst was key money – a present for the landlord. All of this could amount to six months’ rent. To make matters worse, only foreigner-friendly agencies offered one-year contracts.</p>

<p>A mouse was squeaking as Ben hung his laundry. He hated Tokyo at that moment. Money talked all over the world, but here, values took precedence. Respect was thankfully the foremost ideal – until a tenant wished to pay for a vacant apartment, but couldn’t even meet the landlord and prove that he wasn’t a delinquent.</p>

<p>Today was thirty-seven degrees and seventy-five percent humidity. A flash storm was rumbling every evening lately. Constant sweat didn’t exactly facilitate Ben’s psoriasis. Weather, errands, and classwork would leave him no time to go back to dating – and this was just his second week here.</p>

<p>*</p>

<p>The next day, he met the real-life, Japanese version of The Incredibles’ Edna Mode: his new favourite teacher. They wrote essays for the first time; Ben and Nathan checked each other’s.</p>

<p><em>Mr Perfect’s obsidian eyes,</em> the former pictured in his head. <em>Mr Perfect’s long, chiselled figure.</em></p>

<p>Nathan struggled to understand much of Ben’s kanji and grammar. His essay was rife with errors and unnatural phrases. But when he explained cosmic radiation to Ben during recess, none of this mattered.</p>

<p>Next year, he would return to Germany. Ben swallowed his disappointment.</p>

<p>Shin would leave after this term as well. <em>Who among my classmates would become my friend, considering our limited time together?</em></p>

<p>After school, the staff introduced him to the other Israeli students. Two guys and three girls from the other levels. They seemed nice, until one rose above the rest.</p>

<p>Oksana was a Ukrainian-born goth with a slow, Russian accent. No sooner had Ben sat with her in the common area, than an hour flew by.</p>

<p>“I had the same experience when I came here, and it hasn’t gotten any better,” she said regarding the anti-social vibe of Ben’s level five class. “No one’s opened up yet.”</p>

<p>This was coming from a level two student. Several beginner students hung out in the common area every day, did homework, and ate lunch. Those in the upper levels, however, were already too ingrained in their routine to expand their circle. Moreover, they already knew each other.</p>

<p>“Are people really content spending a year just studying and working?” Ben complained.</p>

<p>“It’s so sad,” Oksana said.</p>

<p>He wondered if his classmates simply dismissed <em>his</em> company, the way ex-lovers had.</p>

<p><em>Mr Perfect’s weird, Eastern European accent.</em></p>

<p>When Ben caught sight of Oksana’s bunny trinkets and mentioned visiting a rabbit shrine in Kyoto, goosebumps spread all over her arms.</p>

<p>“You don’t understand, I love bunnies,” she trembled in excitement.</p>

<p>The school staff helped Ben with a new, potential apartment. Its prime location and mint condition didn’t match the suspiciously low rent. The staff checked the listing on a Japanese website, which showed if a tragedy had struck certain buildings. Fire, suicide, murder. Nothing whatsoever.</p>

<p>“You’d better go see it ASAP,” the staff said.</p>

<p>Ben ran to the property. The agency’s day off meant that he’d enter by himself. The realtor instructed him how to unlock the mailbox containing the key, yet no amount of rotating the dial did the trick. It took him ten minutes to realize that the realtor’s left was his right.</p>

<p>Everything was the opposite in Japan.</p>

<p>The apartment was superb, apart from a balcony overlooking the street. Passersby could see right in.</p>

<p>Disappointed, Ben rushed to Kabukicho for his flatmate’s wrestling match.</p>

<p>Japanese girls in lingerie hosted the ‘show’. In a country whose female population dressed like puritans, this was quite the shock. The wrestlers pretended to fight, writhe in pain, and spank each other.</p>

<p>“Please be careful!” the announcer repeated as the crowd cheered. “Do your best!”</p>

<p>The male wrestlers stripped to their underwear.</p>

<p><em>Ryder’s maid costume.</em></p>

<p><em>A large penis.</em></p>

<p>After the match, Ben’s flatmates escorted him back to the apartment. Despite the central location, its street was quiet.</p>

<p>“If you’re not taking it,” the wrestler said in disbelief, “I am.”</p>

<p>The realtor was pressuring him to seal the deal. But it was out of budget.</p>

<p>“This is what I paid per month,” Nathan said regarding the apartment’s move-in fees.</p>

<p>“Well, we have different professions,” Ben said. “You have one, and I don’t.”</p>

<p>Ben wished to find a job in writing, and gain a readership. He wished to live near Shinjuku ni-chome, and return to the game of love. He wished for a stable social circle.</p>

<p>He wished the concept of money disappeared.</p>

<p>At 2:00, he went to bed. Every day was so hectic, that he barely slept six hours. He had not done homework once. Finding an apartment and writing this story came first.</p>

<p><em>An intimate hug</em>, he thought, <em>or any hug</em>.</p>

<p>He forced himself to push dating to the back of his head.</p>

<h2 id="gays-gone-wild-in-tokyo">Gays Gone Wild in Tokyo</h2>

<p>“I am done with public toilet blowjobs,” Ha-joon said upon entering Ben’s bedroom, wearing gym clothes that left little to the imagination.</p>

<p><em>Thank god</em>, Ben thought, devouring natto rice for dinner on his futon mattress.</p>

<p>“You were into them?” Will asked. His faded T-shirt and short joggers accentuated his apparent discomfort, as his legs bent upwards from sitting squashed between the wall and bunk bed.</p>

<p>“Not all of us can host, you know.”</p>

<p>“Tell me about it,” Ben said.</p>

<p>Will blinked in confusion.</p>

<p>“There are love hotels.”</p>

<p>“Some of us are poor,” Mayume said, sitting on the floor and leaning against a wall while glued to Instagram reels of Taylor Swift on his iPad.</p>

<p>“Poor with an iPad?”</p>

<p>“iPad Pro.”</p>

<p>“Sugar daddy,” Ben said. “I’ve been looking for a cheap, second-hand model for school. But I’ll take yours instead.”</p>

<p>“You’re the daddy,” Mayume said. “You can take it if you pay the price. There is one preferred way.”</p>

<p>“I’ll whore myself out for an iPad, I don’t care.”</p>

<p>“So you’ll impregnate me?” Mayume blushed.</p>

<p>“I’ll impregnate Mr Perfect.”</p>

<p>“Whatever,” Mayume said. “I’ll take your seed anyway.”</p>

<p>“To the grave,” Ben said.</p>

<p><em>Ryder’s support. Ryder’s sarcasm.</em></p>

<p>There was a momentary silence as Ben and Mayume competed to see who would smile first. Will seemed more absorbed in his Grindr chat.</p>

<p>“So, public toilets,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“What now,” Mayume muttered.</p>

<p>“I went to this village the other day, and this guy from Hong Kong was the only gay there,” Ha-joon said. “He sucked me off at the only train station, and it wasn’t that great, because he looked at me in a lecherous way that made him look creepy, and didn’t suck well, and blowjobs don’t really do it for me anyway.”</p>

<p>Mayume let go of his iPad. “Blowjobs don’t do it for you?”</p>

<p>Ha-joon shrugged.</p>

<p>“The right one can,” Will smiled.</p>

<p>“Someone who lives one minute from my dorm,” Mayume said, “he’s super short, with thick bangs and a baby face –”</p>

<p>“Are you talking about yourself?” Ha-joon furrowed his brows.</p>

<p>“His long-lost twin,” Ben interjected between sticky, fermented bites.</p>

<p>Mayume got red in the face.</p>

<p>“He’s a nurse, ten years older than me,” he said. “He opened the door and immediately took me to his bed, but there were tons of Psyduck plushies on it.”</p>

<p>Will blinked again.</p>

<p>“A kind of Pokémon,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“And?” Ha-joon snapped.</p>

<p>“Oh, I blew him,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“Okay, but the station manager showed up once we finished,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“What?” Ben put down his chopsticks in disbelief.</p>

<p>“Are you getting deported?” Will asked.</p>

<p>Ha-joon crossed his arms.</p>

<p>“I didn’t even want that guy. I jerked off with my eyes shut just to get it over with,” he said. “Someone came in and peed at the urinals. He swallowed my cum, and when we left the stall, the station manager entered.”</p>

<p>There was only one stall in that restroom. The manager had inspected it as the suspects were washing their hands.</p>

<p>“It’s okay, he won’t do anything,” the swallower had whispered. “Someone must’ve reported it to him.”</p>

<p>Ha-joon had boarded his train to Matsumoto feeling guilt-ridden. Japan was stricter than South Korea. He hadn’t even kissed that guy, nor wanted to.</p>

<p>Then, the only homosexual in his next destination had badgered him for an impromptu fellatio, before his long-distance bus to Tokyo.</p>

<p>A tall Filipino wearing a cap and athleisure, he had done a better job at a larger restroom. They were alone and quiet. Ha-joon closed his eyes again to ejaculate fast. The Filipino had spat everything into the toilet, thanked Ha-joon again, and again, and again, and left.</p>

<p>“So what’s the problem?” Ben asked at present.</p>

<p>“He wasn’t even attracted to them,” Will said.</p>

<p>Ha-joon nodded begrudgingly.</p>

<p>“I met a tourist for coffee and went to his hotel,” Will continued. “He didn’t attract me, but I was horny.”</p>

<p>Will had laid in bed and wooed the French commoner to slow kisses. He’d sought time and touch; the latter had reached down south.</p>

<p>It was supposed to be a long evening of lovemaking. Will had envisioned his long-distance boyfriend as the tourist was servicing him. Yet the opening act turned out as the finale.</p>

<p>“I cleaned for nothing,” Will said at present. “He took a picture of my dick after I came, and that was it.”</p>

<p>Mayume’s eyes lit. “Can I see?”</p>

<p>“Go back to your Psyduck nurse,” Ben scoffed.</p>

<p><em>Ryder’s lips and wide smile.</em></p>

<p>“That was just a quickie,” Mayume shook his head. “He looked my age. Said he didn’t like being so small and adorable.”</p>

<p>Ben grinned.</p>

<p>“They do make them small and adorable here,” he reminisced.</p>

<p>“Their dicks are also small, not gonna lie.”</p>

<p><em>Mr Perfect’s perfect penis.</em></p>

<p>“The problem is shortness, and I don’t mean just size,” Will said. “Everyone’s in a rush these days. What happened to taking your time?”</p>

<p>The foursome considered this as Grindr notifications were popping on Will’s phone.</p>

<p><em>Gay dating enjoyed a world-class privilege: no biological clock</em>. Females thought about kids, or their partner thought about kids, and the clock was ticking.</p>

<p>The downside to this male lack of despair: hookup culture.</p>

<p>Women were notorious for avoiding sex on the first date. Gays did everything in reverse. They met, made little small talk, and explored each other’s bodies, sometimes without even exchanging names.</p>

<p>“I guess you’re all pursuing empty love filled with one-night stands,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“I’m not pursuing love anymore,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“You don’t deserve it anyway,” Mayume muttered.</p>

<p>Ben squinted at him.</p>

<p>“I just need a hot guy in my bed.”</p>

<p>Mayume hopped on Ben’s futon and smirked. The latter fastened the collar of his yukata.</p>

<p><em>Not the guy I meant.</em></p>

<p>“I can’t stop thinking about those kisses that lit a fire in my chest,” he sighed.</p>

<p>“You’re still in love,” Mayume swooned.</p>

<p>“With them, or the way they made you feel?” Will asked.</p>

<p>“You’re just horny, Benedick,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“Then why do I fantasize about having one more conversation?” Ben asked. “Just talking and making each other laugh?”</p>

<p><em>Staring into Cal’s narrow eyes over trashy pizza at Costco.</em></p>

<p>“That’s the most dangerous form of longing,” Will said.</p>

<p>“The most beautiful,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“I hate him,” Ben grouched and hugged his pillow. “He ruined my life.”</p>

<p>Will chuckled. “Which one?”</p>

<p>“Ha ha,” Ben pouted.</p>

<p>“Who cares,” Ha-joon said. “They probably fucked around while you were fucking them.”</p>

<p><em>If only we fucked around.</em></p>

<p>“I don’t fuck around,” Ben said.</p>

<p>The others burst out laughing.</p>

<p>“You fuck around all the time,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p><em>Cal feasting on my ass.</em> Ben joined the laughter, even though it had been three months.</p>

<p>“Grindr is like Pokémon,” he said. “You gotta catch ‘em all.”</p>

<p>Women played in the streets. Men played in the sheets. The latter didn’t believe in delayed gratification; life was too short, the fish in the ocean were too plentiful, and their hormones were raging.</p>

<p><em>In an era where homosexuals could come out of the closet, was same-sex love inside the closet?</em></p>

<p>A wild fairy appeared on 9monsters, the local gay app, every twenty to fifty kilometres in the countryside. They were usually of certain age and appeal. In Faglopolis, however, one roamed every meter. In ni-chome, ten guys every meter.</p>

<p>“Forty million residents, plus tourists, plus commuters,” Ben said. “Unlike most cities, here there will always be a new face.”</p>

<p>And the amount of going down that went down in the world’s shyest country…</p>

<p>Love hotels. Public toilets. Gay saunas and dark rooms. Hostels and capsule hotels weren’t off-limits, either. Ueno Park was famous for cruising.</p>

<p><em>Ryder teasing me with his ass at a hot spring.</em></p>

<p>「友達を募集中」Japanese guys from 9monsters said. (“Looking for friends”)</p>

<p>They usually started off using polite language, and replied casually once you did.</p>

<p>「こんにちは。よろしくお願いします」(“Hello, nice to meet you.”)</p>

<p> Then they requested access to your private album.</p>

<p>「舐めたい」</p>

<p>「フェラーしたい」</p>

<p>「会いたい」</p>

<p>「やりたい」</p>

<p>(“I want to suck you and have sex”)</p>

<p>Although they rarely used 「エッチ」the word for the deed itself. It was too blunt for them.</p>

<p>To stand out on this packed grid, users could Howl: announce an intention on a separate screen.</p>

<p>“I want to meet right away” was the default.</p>

<p>“I can host.”</p>

<p>“I want to go for a drink.”</p>

<p>And, every so often, the gay who got straight to business…</p>

<p>「掘りたい」「掘られたい」(“I want to fuck or get fucked”).</p>

<p>English speakers were rarer than unicorns. Instead, each user was assigned one of nine monsters.</p>

<p>The gay community rivalled zoologists with its physical labels. Twink, bear, silver fox, otter. Anything to facilitate sexual attraction, and accelerate the game.</p>

<p>タチ (“longsword”)  or 攻め (“attacker”) meant top.</p>

<p>ウケ (“receiver”) or ネコ (“cat”) meant bottom.</p>

<p>リバ meant vers.</p>

<p>Biographies of Asians on dating apps often began, or were limited to, their body stats: height, weight, and age, followed by one of the above positions.</p>

<p>Moreover, one inquired about the other’s preferences in bed before even considering enacting them face-to-face. What if he wanted to do something you hated?</p>

<p><em>What if Mr Perfect didn’t want your tongue anywhere near his perfect posterior</em>, Ben sighed internally.</p>

<p>A libertine didn’t simply check if the sex was good before things got serious. Good sex was precisely how things got serious.</p>

<p>Only hopeless romantics spurned bed hopping.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, heavy hitters levelled up on 9monsters. Other apps veiled the ranking system that ruled the rainbow kingdom.</p>

<p>Grindr, for example, catered to foreigners; Tinder, Bumble, and Hinge were the vanilla versions. Almost all the Japanese guys there could speak at least basic English. But there were still some Asians whose collection was “Asian only”.</p>

<p>Jack’d dominated in South Korea, while Hornet, in Taiwan.</p>

<p>No matter their country, no matter their shyness, every confirmed bachelor based their libido on Sex and the City’s Samantha Jones.</p>

<p>“What’s a good body count?” Ben asked as the others were texting guys on various apps.</p>

<p>“Oh, we’re not gonna go there,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>Ben didn’t dare ask for their stats. Too low, and you were a pariah. Too high, and you were a whore.</p>

<p>“I always wonder, but it makes me jealous,” Ben said. “Who’s the bigger player? It’s a rabbit hole I don’t want to go down into.”</p>

<p>“I thought you love going down holes,” Will said.</p>

<p><em>Then let me,</em> Ben almost blurted.</p>

<p>Girls were either hard to get or slutty. Gays were either ugly or sexy.</p>

<p>Poo pirates loved sailing so much, that they had originated outbreaks of a sexually transmitted diseases outside Africa. HIV, monkeypox: somehow, whenever an admiral went on a safari, it brought a souvenir on board.</p>

<p>It got to a point where an HIV clinic or the line to a monkeypox vaccine became breeding grounds for fresh bacteria.</p>

<p>“They don’t play it hard to get,” Ben said. “They play it hard to get again.”</p>

<p>The first date was easy: it immediately led to sex. The second date was a fool’s errand.</p>

<p><em>Cal. Ryder. Mr Perfect.</em></p>

<p>“Fucking text him already,” Ha-joon said. “You’ve been talking about him for almost a year.”</p>

<p>“No,” Ben said. “He hates me.”</p>

<p>“But he contacted you at some point, right?” Will asked.</p>

<p><em>They all did.</em></p>

<p>“That was just the nostalgia talking,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“Same way Cal texted me out of nowhere just to tell me about his new relationship.”</p>

<p>“Fucking block him.”</p>

<p>Ben frowned into his pillow.</p>

<p>“I can’t understand why he did that,” he said.</p>

<p>“Why, why, 왜,” Ha-joon mocked. “You can bang your head against the wall, or just bang a guy against a wall.”</p>

<p>“Or get gang-banged,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“They’re gonna do what they want no matter what,” Will said. “You might as well do the same.”</p>

<h2 id="the-japanese-twink-who-gave-the-best-orgasms">The Japanese Twink Who Gave the Best Orgasms</h2>

<p><em>The morning after the Tokyo Pride weekend where I’d met Stephen, I woke with a violent hickey. My throat looked like it had been punched.</em></p>

<p><em>Evidently, a police search wasn’t the only outcome of a late-night lip service in the streets of ni-chome.</em></p>

<p><em>I zipped my jacket all the way to my chin. At the Embassy of Israel in Tokyo, I checked if I could extend my visa and stay in Japan.</em></p>

<p><em>“I can’t help you,” the staff bellowed through the intercom. “Go to the Embassy of Japan in Tel-Aviv.”</em></p>

<p><em>He didn’t even let me inside.</em></p>

<p><em>His Israeli rudeness made me grouch. The last two and a half months spent traveling in this country had been the happiest of my life.</em>  </p>

<p><em>Tired and concerned, I returned to my hotel. A whole new day of sightseeing – yet traveling wasn’t on my mind. Only the end of this trip.</em></p>

<p><em>I spent hours in my room, scouring the internet for information about cheap travel destinations. My head was swimming with anxiety about returning to Israel.</em></p>

<p><em>“What would you do?” I texted Will.</em></p>

<p><em>“I would stop and feel the stillness,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>In the evening, a Japanese guy came over. He was very short and vaguely cute. I wasn’t particularly into him, as toned as his abs were.</em></p>

<p><em>Then he opened up for me, and I ascended to paradise.</em></p>

<p><em>He pleasured me so much, that I ejaculated in an instant. It always took me a long time to see god, partially because I hadn’t been with a guy who had turned me on enough. But there was something about this twink’s giddy-up, loud moans, and back door. I didn’t even need to fantasize about greener pastures, or do anything but lie on my back and smile.</em></p>

<p><em>We dozed off in each other’s arms. When we woke, round two of his rodeo featured a wilder ride.</em></p>

<p><em>Then he left. Back to Osaka, his hometown. And I, brisk from sex that triumphed porn, returned to ni-chome for the third night in a row.</em></p>

<p><em>Monday did not match my energy. The bars and clubs were nigh vacant. I talked to a few guys, with whom I felt zero connection. The gay scene in Tokyo came to life on weekends, and died on weekdays.</em></p>

<p><em>But I had a mission. I would lead a fabulous lifestyle, despite never having sold a single word of my prose.</em></p>

<p><em>So another Japanese twink came to my hotel room. He was very young, very short, very vaguely cute, and had abs just as rock-hard. I pumped him for a long time, until we fell asleep midway through.</em></p>

<p><em>*</em></p>

<p><em>The next day, I woke tired. Tired from a wild weekend of clubbing, days of worrying about my future, and months of inadequate slumber. Stephen had a day off from university, so we met at his share house in Akabane, an unobtrusive suburb in the northern outskirts of Tokyo.</em></p>

<p><em>Old school video games, music posters, and anime merch filled his bedroom, fitting of a video game music composition major.</em></p>

<p><em>We spent the whole day talking. He’d prepared a list of questions, having read every post on my blog several times.</em></p>

<p><em>He was very observant. He asked things I hesitated to answer, and made remarks I preferred he hadn’t.</em></p>

<p><em>“I feel like you have constant anxiety,” he said. “You seem really anxious.”</em></p>

<p><em>I fidgeted nervously in his arms. Every now and then, we stared into each other’s eyes.</em></p>

<p><em>“I want your eyes,” he said in admiration. Even though he was the one with the large, piercing blue ones.</em></p>

<p><em>We differed in many aspects, such as taste in food and music, but shared worldviews. I sang to him a sad song I’d written – the first person to hear my music – and he stayed silent.</em></p>

<p><em>He took me to my first Japanese curry restaurant and karaoke parlour. Carly Rae Jepsen’s Run Away with Me was his choice, after I’d featured it on my blog.</em></p>

<p><em>At night, we strolled around his neighbourhood. Narrow streets led to dead ends; tiny apartments, and the rare sight of an elder local. So quiet – so dark – so deserted.</em></p>

<p><em>He took me to his favourite alley, as short as it was cramped. It felt like a different city on a different planet.</em></p>

<p><em>We’d entered a pocket reality, in that brief moment, standing still and listening to nothingness. I was a bit restless, worried about intruding on the neighbours.</em></p>

<p><em>At the nearby Arakawa River, he showed me the wooden deck where he often passed time.</em></p>

<p><em>I told him about the police incident from last night.</em></p>

<p><em>“It seems like weird things keep happening to you, and I’m not surprised,” he said. “You have this sort of gravitas.”</em></p>

<p><em>He couldn’t have been more wrong. It was bad luck.</em></p>

<p><em>“People constantly give you presents,” he insisted. “They take you on two-day trips and pay for everything.”</em></p>

<p><em>“That’s just Japanese people being nice,” I said, recalling an example of this from last week.</em></p>

<p><em>The sky was exceptionally bright. Light pollution made ten o’clock at night seem like sundown.</em></p>

<p><em>We sat on the bank. The dim river was flowing quietly yet swiftly. Bats were flying above us; grass smelled of rain. The tip of my shoe was forming ripples on the water. The only sounds came from our infrequent words, and vehicles on the distant bridge. Sometimes, the quacks of ducks.</em></p>

<p><em>It felt like déjà vu. For the second time this trip, I spent hours with someone I’d felt an immediate connection to. We delved into personal matters and topics that made me cry.</em></p>

<p><em>Still, he was the first person to read my blog back-to-back, and bring it up. To my surprise, he had screenshotted certain passages, and saved certain photos.</em></p>

<p><em>“I feel like you’re the first person to actually see me,” I said.</em></p>

<p><em>I knew that I would remember this moment forever.</em></p>

<p><em>He read this thought as I was typing it. It felt like we were alone in the universe.</em></p>

<p><em>Then he asked me more questions. I found myself babbling about the people I’d hung out with on this trip.</em></p>

<p><em>“See? You’re surrounded by love,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>It didn’t feel like that. They might have enjoyed my company, but hadn’t seemed interested in what I’d had to say.</em></p>

<p><em>“You’re equalling what you write with who you are, as if they’re the same thing,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>“They are.”</em></p>

<p><em>Suddenly, it hit me: being read was the same for me as being seen.</em></p>

<p><em>I’d been fantasising about acquiring a readership ever since I’d begun writing at the age of seven. Sometimes I wished I hadn’t. There were easier dreams to pick.</em></p>

<p><em>Stephen was my only reader.</em></p>

<p><em>“<strong>Because to me, you’re the coolest guy in the world,” he grinned</strong>.</em></p>

<p><em>“You wanna hear something weird?” I asked. “I don’t really miss people. It’s easy for me to move on. But now that I think about everyone I met on this trip… I would like to see them again.”</em></p>

<p><em>He couldn’t relate to that.</em></p>

<p><em>“When I think about the people I can’t see again,” he said, “it hurts.”</em></p>

<p><em>My heart sank in shame. He was seven years younger than me, but more experienced. I’d never ached like him.</em></p>

<p><em>“I think I’ll miss you,” I said, meaning it.</em></p>

<p><em>We walked to Iwabuchi Watergate, also known as Suicide Bridge. Nicknamed after the corpses of jumpers that had washed to the water gate. A destroyed, faceless Jesus statue stood nearby to commemorate the victims.</em></p>

<p><em>Then it was time to head to the station for the last train.</em></p>

<p><em>Neither of us wanted to part. Yet I was worried about my hotel barring him entrance.</em></p>

<p><em>“C’mon, it’ll be fine,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>“I don’t know,” I said, embarrassed that someone else had already stayed there. “I don’t think I can have you over.”</em></p>

<p><em>“Okay,” he said, and walked away.</em></p>

<p><em>I stood outside the station. He didn’t look back.</em></p>

<p><em>He ripped the band-aid so fast, that it burned.</em></p>

<p><em>“Stephen!” I shouted, chasing him after a minute of rapid thinking, or rather feeling. “I want you to come.”</em></p>

<p><em>I couldn’t let today’s final note to be rejection. Not after telling him things I’d never told anyone, and crying multiple times in his presence.</em></p>

<p><em>“I thought I’d never see you again, so I figured it’d be easier to just go,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>We hopped on the train to Shinjuku. I found myself tearing up again. By Yotsuya station, where we switched trains, my face was damp.</em></p>

<p><em>I got into the second train – packed like sardines, despite the late hour – and stumbled upon two Israelis I’d met ten days ago in Takayama.</em></p>

<p><em>“No way,” I exclaimed in Hebrew and wiped my cheeks. “What are the odds?”</em></p>

<p><em>We had a few minutes to chat before my stop. Indeed, what were the odds of running into them in the world’s largest city, inside a crowded train?</em></p>

<p><em>I was happy to see them again. But I didn’t get to run into the one person I’d longed to see in Tokyo. The first person on this trip I’d fancied, and tried to find because we hadn’t exchanged numbers.</em></p>

<p><em>Back in my hotel room, Stephen gave me a quarter of an edible.</em></p>

<p><em>“This trip is all about trying new things, right?” he asked, after I hesitated to take it.</em></p>

<p><em>I put it in my mouth. He said it would take some time to kick in.</em></p>

<p><em>“You smell like a bookshelf,” he muttered when we got into bed. “A cosy library.”</em></p>

<p><em>“How can you tell?” I asked, sniffing myself, yet not detecting anything.</em></p>

<p><em>“I’m like a wolfhound,” he said. “I can always tell who’s at home.”</em></p>

<p><em>I dozed off before the edible could work its magic. Or maybe it did, and simply made me sleepy. I woke in the middle of the night, slightly lacking balance.</em></p>

<h2 id="alls-fair-in-love-and-real-estate">All’s Fair in Love and Real Estate</h2>

<p>“If you could live in a perfect world and be God,” Nathan asked during recess, “would you give up your sense of smell and taste in return?”</p>

<p><em>The endless kiss with Cal that unified our bodies.</em> Ben caught himself daydreaming, and echoed Sandro’s ‘yes’. Kacie said no.</p>

<p>“My girlfriend also declined,” Nathan said. He, Sandro, and Ben – three Western guys – failed to understand the two Asian girls.</p>

<p>“If I eliminate suffering, it would make people evil,” Nathan’s girlfriend had argued. “Suffering is a part of life.”</p>

<p>“But you use medicine, right?” Nathan had asked. “So you try to avoid it. You wouldn’t save your family and your dog and all of humanity in exchange for your taste buds?”</p>

<p>After several minutes like this, tears had welled in her eyes.</p>

<p>“I had no idea she felt cornered,” Nathan said at present. “As far as I’m concerned, discussing the necessity of suffering is like making small talk about the weather.”</p>

<p>His new Japanese girlfriend had said that no one had delved into such matters with her, and asked him to stop.</p>

<p>“But that’s sweeping it under the rug,” Ben said.</p>

<p><em>Mr Perfect’s tongue tracing my upper lip.</em></p>

<p>“We did get into the same argument again,” Nathan said. “I told her sixty times that I wasn’t trying to attack her, just figure out what my partner thought about suffering.”</p>

<p>Ben would’ve also interrogated her until making sense of her illogical stance.</p>

<p>“Either I’m dumb and have no ability to read the room,” Nathan said, mentioning a common complaint in Japan regarding foreigners, “or I’m just an asshole. Am I that socially awkward? Like, where’s the line? I can’t understand, is it a cultural thing?”</p>

<p>“She’s going to dump you,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“Yeah,” Nathan sighed.</p>

<p>He seemed more confused than upset.</p>

<p>“I want a partner with whom I can have these discussions,” he said.</p>

<p><em>Were Japanese people too reticent for that?</em> Ben had never argued with a local before. He’d also never been in a relationship with one.</p>

<p>“Even the order in which they date is the opposite,” Nathan continued over lunch at a Thai restaurant, after Ben had invited Sandro and him. “They go out, do the ‘kokuhaku’” (confession of love) “on the third date, become a couple, and then have sex.”</p>

<p><em>Unless they were gay.</em></p>

<p>“Regardless of order, I believe that every relationship must endure two tests,” Nathan said. “A big change, and a big fight.”</p>

<p>With Ryder, Ben had survived neither.</p>

<p>Nathan pointed out how, when Japanese couples broke up, they returned to the dating scene the next day, as if nothing had transpired.</p>

<p>“You become a couple so fast,” he said, “that it carries less weight.”</p>

<p>In the Western world, people tested the waters across all three bases before hitting home run. A break-up actually broke your heart.</p>

<p>Ben looked down at his plate. His heart had been broken even without an official break-up. A relationship wasn’t a stage he’d reached, despite two months of dating, living together, and discussing weddings.</p>

<p>*</p>

<p>He spent the weekend in bed, writing for hours without getting up for food or a drink.</p>

<p><em>Missionary.</em></p>

<p><em>Cowboy.</em></p>

<p><em>Reverse cowboy.</em></p>

<p><em>Ryder’s incredulous moan.</em></p>

<p>His heart skipped a beat upon publishing the first chapter of this story. Months of preparation had led to this. Yet by the end of the day, none of his friends acknowledged it.</p>

<p>Sex and the City had premiered as a dark dramedy about the death of love. After viewership had risen, it had concluded as a fairy tale rom-com. But throughout its run, one detail had remained realistic: Carrie Bradshaw’s closest friends never read, let alone brought up, her columns.</p>

<p>Neither did Ben’s friends and family. After years of daily writing, pain from romantic defeats, and life-changing growth, nothing had made him prouder than crafting this new story.</p>

<p>He felt betrayed by every person in his life.</p>

<p>“Stop being such a baby,” he imagined Ha-joon saying. “People do what they want.”</p>

<p>“That’s why I don’t expect anything out of anyone,” Will would have said, if they were here.</p>

<p>He continued apartment hunting instead. Two weeks of daily searches had yielded several good options, which rejected him automatically.</p>

<p>In the evening, Ben’s first visit to the grocery store raised his spirits.</p>

<p>In Japan, supermarkets opened with a takeout section. Sushi, salads, grilled fish, noodles. Half off around dinner time.</p>

<p>Then there was fresh produce, packed and presented like in a hotel. Fruit and vegetables native to both the East and West. But the cherry on top were mini melons and square watermelons.</p>

<p>The fish section was a hunter-gatherer’s heaven. Fresh, clean, and cheap.</p>

<p>Finally, bagging stations prevented customers from holding up the queue at the cash register.</p>

<p>After indulging on daifuku and sashimi, Ben went to bed at three AM.</p>

<p><em>Doggy.</em></p>

<p><em>On the floor.</em></p>

<p><em>Against the wall.</em></p>

<p><em>Head buried in ass.</em></p>

<p>He woke too sick to leave bed or eat anything. He hated how his dreams depended on other people.</p>

<p>The following day, a middle-aged fisherman he’d met in Onomichi visited Tokyo, and offered to accompany Ben to a new real estate agency. The realtor showed them an apartment in Shinjuku that ticked off all his boxes: location, budget, and condition.</p>

<p><em>Mr Perfect’s tender whispers.</em></p>

<p>Perhaps it was the presence of a Japanese companion. Perhaps this agency had a different pool of properties. Whatever it was, Ben said yes on the spot.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5v5hyNeHbOQ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="satbc" /><category term="akabane" /><category term="ni-chome" /><category term="shin-okubo" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“You see that buddy over there? I fucked him. See that buddy over there? I fucked him too. I never thought I’d see them again.” Sex and the City (season 1, episode 3)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 2: It’s a Masc4Masc World</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/10/06/chapter-2-its-a-masc4masc-world-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0-%E7%94%B7%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%84%E7%94%B7%E3%82%92%E5%8B%9F%E9%9B%86%E4%B8%AD.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 2: It’s a Masc4Masc World" /><published>2024-10-06T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-10-06T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/10/06/chapter-2-its-a-masc4masc-world-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0%E3%83%BB%E7%94%B7%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%84%E7%94%B7%E3%82%92%E5%8B%9F%E9%9B%86%E4%B8%AD</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/10/06/chapter-2-its-a-masc4masc-world-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0-%E7%94%B7%E3%82%89%E3%81%97%E3%81%84%E7%94%B7%E3%82%92%E5%8B%9F%E9%9B%86%E4%B8%AD.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“I felt it was time to call it a night. I had never felt so invisible in my entire life.”</p>

  <p>Sex and the City (season 1, episode 2)</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="first-day-of-school">First Day of School</h2>

<p>Everywhere a homo went, there was only one question in his head.</p>

<p><em>Any cute boys?</em></p>

<p>First day of school, he would scour the class.</p>

<p>First day of work, he would scour the office.</p>

<p>First day of volunteering, he would scour the guesthouse.</p>

<p>Every outing to a bar was like a secret service agent scouting for a target. Or a dog sniffing for drugs.</p>

<p>Yet starting today, all Ben could get high off was pen and paper. He was a student again.</p>

<p>He slept three hours and rushed to his new school with bloodshot eyes. The Starbucks cup from 7-11 in his hand was like a chef with takeaway. Yet desperate times called for desperate measures.</p>

<p>Surveying sixty new students during orientation proved exciting enough to rouse Ben. Most were tall, white guys.</p>

<p>“Does anyone intend to buy a bicycle?” the principal asked. “Every bicycle in Japan needs to be registered, and it’s hard to find parking. Even slight offences, such as driving tickets, can ruin all your future visa applications. So please let us know in advance.”</p>

<p>“You also need the school’s approval every time you leave the country,” another staffer said.</p>

<p>Ben smiled. <em>Back to academic rules and complaining about homework. Back to going out with international friends and stressing over exams.</em></p>

<p>For the first time in his life, he would live in a big city: the biggest on Earth.</p>

<p>It occurred to him that he was not nervous at all. Meeting a plethora of new people, relocating to a new country, being on his own. Only two threats made his chest constrict nowadays. Love and finance.</p>

<p>“I love Japan, but the people are so polite, that it becomes fake,” a new French student voiced Ben’s thoughts from last night at a conveyor belt sushi in Kabukicho. “I want to find real friends who are honest.”</p>

<p>A blue-eyed ginger with a baseball cap who towered over the locals, his Japanese girlfriend had recently gotten pregnant.</p>

<p>“A foreigner who’d been living here for forty years had once told me that I would never become Japanese,” Ben said. “That’s okay. I don’t want to. I want to be a foreigner who lives in Japan.”</p>

<p>“Yeah, the people in Tokyo, they look so lifeless,” the French said. “They go to the office, scroll on their phone inside a train, work all day, and return home.”</p>

<p>Yet in true Tokyo fashion, Ben declined the offer to continue the conversation at an izakaya over drinks. He nearly fell asleep at the restaurant.</p>

<p>*</p>

<p>There were two hundred students in Ben’s Japanese language school in Shin Okubo, and eleven in his class. They hailed from Germany, Italy, France, Ukraine, Switzerland, South Korea, Taiwan, and the US.</p>

<p><em>What was he doing here?</em> Ben freaked out the moment he sat down.</p>

<p>The Korean looked like someone he had dated in Busan. Short and skinny, with monolid eyes, oversized nineties streetwear, and a baseball cap. This was the rare Korean twink, bashful and soft-spoken, who seemed more Japanese.</p>

<p><em>An anchovy</em>, Ben imagined Ha-joon saying.</p>

<p>Shin introduced himself in a voice that was barely audible. Ben immediately resolved to befriend him.</p>

<p>“So,” the teacher, a middle-aged Japanese woman, said after the introductions. “How does everyone study kanji?”</p>

<p>The students all blinked downward.</p>

<p>“I pray at a temple,” Ben joked in Japanese.</p>

<p>“Eh?” the teacher chuckled in confusion.</p>

<p>The students glanced at Ben without laughing. He wanted to drop out.</p>

<p>Recess brought better interactions. Kacie was a quiet girl from Taichung who marvelled at Ben’s exploits in Taiwan. Kristen was an American graphic designer who worked with Japanese rock bands, and attended their concerts weekly. Zelda radiated a high-fashion cross between elf and fairy. Aubrey seemed like the anime-inspired little sister of Billie Eilish, with silver pins on her scarlet hair, a doll-like face, and camouflage cargo pants.</p>

<p>Sandro was a handsome Italian with a pointed bone structure that accentuated his ocean eyes and sandy hair. Tall and athletic, he spoke eloquently with received pronunciation from a London relocation.</p>

<p>Yet it was Nathan, a German software engineer, who made frequent conversations with Ben. He was easy and engrossing to talk to, like an affable bust of a young Roman emperor come to life.</p>

<p>With thick, wavy hair escaping his cap, a trimmed beard, fair skin, and subtle features, Ben found himself staring at Nathan’s electric blue eyes. He recalled predicting on the first day of his two degrees who his friends would be. Back then, he was too shy to initiate any hangouts after class. Yet now, when he waited for Nathan in the afternoon and noticed how every student went to their own way, he returned to his share house disappointed.</p>

<p>He was the only student who had enrolled straight into an advanced class. By level five out of eight, everyone had been studying at this school for at least six months.</p>

<p><em>They already knew each other</em>, he sighed_. But didn’t they want to at least grab lunch?_</p>

<p>“The guys all have Japanese girlfriends, too,” he complained to Mayume on the phone.</p>

<p>“Straggots,” Mayume muttered. “Bland chicken is at the top of the food pyramid in Asia.”</p>

<p>“Seriously though, those white-guy, Asian-girl couples are literally everywhere,” Ben said. “But never the opposite.”</p>

<p>“We should follow their example,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“In your dreams,” Ben hung up.</p>

<p>He crashed on his bed and browsed rental apartments online with zombie eyes. Mayume, Ha-joon, and Will went out to ni-chome at night. But Ben was too tired and busy to join them. All he could do was recall the past.</p>

<h2 id="tokyo-pride-in-ni-chome">Tokyo Pride in Ni-Chome</h2>

<p><em>Saturday night at the most popular gay club in Japan, on the eve of Pride.</em></p>

<p><em>Muscle shirts, alcohol, pop music, and go-go boys. The music was loud, the people were countless,</em> <em>and the kissing was omnipresent.</em></p>

<p><em>I walked for five minutes from my hotel to Shinjuku ni-chome, Tokyo’s queer paradise. A rainbow torii graced the entrance of a famous bar. It was so crowded, that most of the patrons were drinking outside.</em></p>

<p><em>Then I stood in line to the club: my first one. I was nervous, but this trip was about trying new things.</em></p>

<p><em>Inside was more teeming than a bakery with free buns. I got sake and squeezed my way to the dance floor.</em></p>

<p><em>It felt weird. I never danced. A few people were standing in the back with their drinks in hand, looking uncomfortable. I forced myself to not join them.</em></p>

<p><em>So I started to move my body. I mimicked other dancers, and slowly let loose. The floor-to-ceiling mirrors almost made me cringe.</em></p>

<p><em>It didn’t help that there was a couple next to me on a mission to break the world record for longest smooch in history. They sucked each other’s faces like oxygen masks in vacuum.</em></p>

<p><em>I grew hot. The cramped bodies engulfing me reeked. Disco balls dazzled while neon spotlights pranced around the dim party. It appeared as though I was the only lone wolf.</em></p>

<p><em>A Japanese guy took me aside, handed me a wireless earphone, and put on Nicki Minaj. We listened to her rapping as ABBA proclaimed everyone ‘dancing queens’.</em></p>

<p><em>I returned to my spot in the middle of the floor, hungry for a better encounter. Beefy go-go boys were dancing on the screens. Three muscular Asians with perky bangs and tank tops were making good use of their tongues in a three-way kiss.</em></p>

<p><em>Then a skinny guy with bubble-gum pink bangs and oversized clothes danced with me. He kept trying to touch me, yet I wasn’t feeling it.</em></p>

<p><em>The tallest guy in the club walked in. He wore black designer streetwear and heaps of silver jewelry, like an Asian fashion model from Berlin.</em></p>

<p><em>Everyone seemed to know him, or want to know him. He greeted partygoers with a gracious smile, accompanied by a guy that reminded me of Middle Easterners from back home.</em></p>

<p><em>The pink twink had moved on to other candidates, pecking them one after the other.</em></p>

<p><em>After some time, the Asian-German started dancing shirtless. Like an underwear model, he had a six pack and perfect skin.</em></p>

<p><em>Bodies were bumping against each other, making shots of alcohol spill. Sweat and musk were filling the air. The model’s face beamed brighter than the disco lights. The entire scene didn’t seem real.</em></p>

<p><em>Suddenly, I felt déjà vu. This packed nightclub made me feel ecstatic and wretched, just like a recent temple stay in Koya-san.</em></p>

<p><em>I enjoyed dancing and partaking in a liberated, queer atmosphere – yet felt like rotten meat. The same dejection darkened the pink twink’s face. He was ogling the crowd in a defeated pout, after his hunt had failed.</em></p>

<p><em>So I closed my eyes. Enough worrying about my appearance. Enough fretting over all the couples kissing.</em></p>

<p><em>Not knowing who was around me, how appetizing and better at dancing they seemed, and whether they were watching me, warmed my cold feet. I whirled my body. I danced. I focused on my physicality and the music blaring in my ears, the lyrics I was yelling, and the songs that uplifted me.</em></p>

<p><em>I let the sea of people push me, move me, relocate me, without seeing where my shoes landed. Nothing mattered at this moment: the spot I inhabited, the swaying of my hips, or my invisibility next to all the Asian Adonis. I felt déjà vu again, this time to Shodoshima, where I’d cycled up a deserted mountain a week after Koya-san, gazed at a foggy port beneath me, and screamed with bliss.</em></p>

<p><em>I felt free.</em></p>

<p><em>A nightclub was the last place I’d expected to elicit that. I’d always lied in order to skip parties and stay in my room.</em></p>

<p><em>Now, I cracked a smile. I stopped craving the gourmet meals around me, I quit revolting at my insipidity, and instead grinned, and chuckled, and laughed.</em></p>

<p><em>Was this me? Was it really happening?</em></p>

<p><em>Yes, I was, it was – and I found myself in seventh heaven.</em></p>

<p><em>As singers continued to roar and dancers to shove me, a pair of arms touched my torso.</em></p>

<p><em>I opened my eyes. A Japanese guy was holding my waist, chortling as if snorting laughing gas.</em></p>

<p><em>“Wait a second!” he yelled in Japanese, when I followed his lead and danced with him. He could barely stand from all the laughter.</em></p>

<p><em>I must have embarrassed myself. He excused himself and left. Disappointed, I danced with my mouth wide and eyes shut.</em></p>

<p><em>That was when another set of arms embraced me.</em></p>

<p><em>They belonged to a white guy with a skirt, emo bangs, and cat ears. We danced together, until I found myself challenging the world-record couple.</em></p>

<p><em>Then he led me outside.</em></p>

<p><em>My first breath of fresh air in four hours. My ears were ringing. I felt like I’d suffered permanent hearing damage.</em></p>

<p><em>We found a quiet, external staircase. I learned that he was a British student of video game music, who also preferred Japan to his country of origin.</em></p>

<p><em>“Are you high?” he asked. My uninhibited dancing had given him this impression.</em></p>

<p><em>“No,” I said. “I had one sake. This is actually my first time clubbing.”</em></p>

<p><em>“It is?”</em></p>

<p><em>I explained my lifelong avoidance of clubs, and tonight’s inconceivable fun.</em></p>

<p><em>“So you were high on life,” he said. A phrase I’d never heard.</em></p>

<p><em>“I want to use it as a title for my next post,” I said, transfixed. By now, he’d learned about my blog.</em></p>

<p><em>“No, that’s so cliché.”</em></p>

<p><em>“True. I probably embarrassed myself way too much already.”</em></p>

<p><em>“Yeah, that was kind of embarrassing,” he said. “But that’s why I approached you.”</em></p>

<p><em>The more we talked, the more we found out how much we had in common. Certain beloved anime, or running a website dedicated to our passions. Dreaming of a career in arts. He had also given himself an unorthodox nickname. Every revelation like this made way for disbelief and laughter. Lots and lots of laughter.</em></p>

<p><em>Shivering on a building’s staircase at witching hour, we marvelled at our shared interests, to the point where it felt exhilarating.</em></p>

<p><em>He was six years younger than me. Yet he was already explaining the lore of ni-chome, where he’d seen men do a lot more than exchange fluids in the alleys.</em></p>

<p><em>His sapphire eyes mesmerized me. His articulate voice, I could listen to for hours. A British accent that had become American, for the locals’ comprehension.</em></p>

<p><em>Who was this person? Was this really happening?</em></p>

<p><em>I fell asleep with him in my bed at 4:00, no longer a rubbish bag in a patisserie of delicacies.</em></p>

<h2 id="gym-twins-or-gay-couple">Gym Twins or Gay Couple?</h2>

<p>Sunset outside the Museum of Modern Art, Tokyo. Ben waited until Mayume arrived late in sweaty sportswear.</p>

<p>“Why do you run every night?” Ben asked. “You’re already skinny.”</p>

<p>Mayume was panting heavily. A Japanese twunk in short shorts jogged past them.</p>

<p>“Oh.”</p>

<p><em>A visit to the Imperial Palace in Tokyo was a dangerous act of sightseeing</em>. Not because it was one of the only places in Japan under heavy security. Joggers darted past you every second. Daikancho-dori, the road circling the Palace, might as well be renamed Racecourse Avenue.</p>

<p>“You could’ve replied that you were running late,” Ben said, trying to focus on Mayume instead. “You’re so bad at texting.”</p>

<p>“You realize this just now?” Mayume asked.</p>

<p>“No, it was clear from like a week after we met.”</p>

<p>“Good, then it’s a reminder.” Mayume chugged from a bottle of water bigger than him. “I’m going to Mongolia. Can’t bear this scorching weather.”</p>

<p>“For vacation?”</p>

<p>“I’ll come back after a month,” he said, spelling ‘c-u-m’ out loud. “July 31 to be exact.”</p>

<p>“I don’t care,” Ben said. “Have fun milking goats on the mountains.”</p>

<p>“You never cared from the beginning.”</p>

<p>“True.”</p>

<p>They smiled at each other. Smooth legs were running wild in short shorts, as if a road lined with skyscrapers and a river was their natural habitat, more than any park in Tokyo.</p>

<p>“I’m fine with it,” Mayume said, beginning to walk.</p>

<p>“You’re dead on the inside.”</p>

<p>“How about the outside?”</p>

<p>Ben followed Mayume toward the Palace.</p>

<p>“Annoying on the outside.”</p>

<p>“C’mon, say something worse.”</p>

<p>“Mr Perfect saw that I moved to Japan and ignored it,” Ben said. “Nothing worse than that.”</p>

<p>“You said you were over him.”</p>

<p>“I am over him,” Ben said. “Shut up.”</p>

<p>“Only your cock can shut my mouth, dad.”</p>

<p>Ben smiled in exasperation. The sun was setting over the understated Palace gate. Tiled roofs and white walls, reconstructed to match their ancient origin, were eclipsed by cutting-edge skyscrapers and lush trees.</p>

<p>“Why are Cal and Ryder watching my stories again?” Ben asked, checking his phone.</p>

<p>“Cal is a piece of shit,” Mayume said. “Fuck that asshole.”</p>

<p>“I already did.”</p>

<p>“Ryder is waiting for you to message him,” Mayume continued. “But he’ll say something shitty, even if he wants you.”</p>

<p>“I will never give him the satisfaction,” Ben said. “I have self-respect now.”</p>

<p>“Sounds like a red herring.”</p>

<p>“Do you even know what a red herring is?”</p>

<p>A jogging bodybuilder turned Ben and Mayume’s heads.</p>

<p><em>No, wait, I love you</em>, Ben thought.  </p>

<p>“I’m ovulating,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>They started walking in the bodybuilder’s direction, when Will and Ha-joon arrived.</p>

<p>“There you are,” Will said, wearing designer activewear with no signs of perspiration.</p>

<p>“I can’t believe none of you fuckers told me about this place,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>Ben didn’t know where to look. At the beautiful landscape, at the Imperial Palace Gardens, or at Ha-joon’s arms. Then a group of Scandinavian tourists distracted him.</p>

<p>“I feel like I’m wired to notice hot guys everywhere I go,” he said. “It’s like I have a radar.”</p>

<p><em>Better not to mention obsessing over their height compared to mine.</em></p>

<p>“You missed some man flesh at the club,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“Oh yeah?” Ben asked, gauging whether his eyes were looking up or down at Ha-joon’s. The latter showed the profile of a hot new mutual from Instagram.</p>

<p>“There was also an influencer from Brazil,” Will said and showed a video of the club. “We got a lot of followers.”</p>

<p>“That’s what he was good for?” Mayume chuckled. “Maybe I should also do PR for a club.”</p>

<p>“They call it public relations for a reason,” Will smiled.</p>

<p><em>That should be the new code for an open relationship.</em></p>

<p>“Looks like a regular night,” Ben muttered, watching the hyper-sexual crowd at the club.</p>

<p>Japan was notorious for being the most polite, reserved, and respectful country on Earth. Public displays of affection glared like gunshots. Guys who hit on girls in bars often started with an apology.</p>

<p><em>A Japanese gay club was the last place I expected to host the Sexual Olympics.</em></p>

<p>Even in assertive South Korea or gay-friendly Taiwan, guys didn’t edge toward make-out competitions or make pickup so obvious. And “hunting” was an actual hookup term in Korean. The Japanese dance floor was a hunting ground for hungry prey.</p>

<p>In a society too fond of repression, this was the place to release your inner beast. Whether surrounded by friends or strangers, an outing became a game, a competition, to see who would score the most.</p>

<p><em>Yet I could never cook as well as weightlifters who prepped their meals.</em></p>

<p>“Watch those masc4masc guys squeal like girls when the roach starts flying,” Ha-joon said at Will’s video.</p>

<p>“Like when you asked me to come kill it last week?” Will asked, and unsheathed a vodka flask from his chest bag.</p>

<p><em>Masc4masc was the gay version of a modelizer.</em> They dated only gym rats. Like cats on steroids, they evolved past the natural order of things, and dined exclusively at steakhouses.</p>

<p>Once this term took off and received criticism, gays got creative.</p>

<p><em>No fems.</em></p>

<p><em>Into muscle.</em></p>

<p><em>Be manly.</em></p>

<p><em>Like athletic.</em></p>

<p><em>Only into straight acting.</em></p>

<p>Who said that gym bros were airheads? They knew their way around a thesaurus. But not around other body types.</p>

<p>‘Cute’ didn’t cut it anymore. Why would someone hurt themselves on the shoulder blades of a scrawny nerd, when they could climb a thick hunk instead?</p>

<p>Ben ducked under branches as the foursome circled the river. Passersby kept glimpsing Ha-joon and Will.</p>

<p>“Y’all haters corny with that masc4masc mess,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“Next time you’re in ni-chome,” Will said, “drink when you see a couple that looks like twins.”</p>

<p>“I don’t have time for ni-chome,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“Good,” Will said, and sipped from his vodka. “You’d ruin your liver like this.”</p>

<p><em>His dark eyes seemed an inch higher than mine.</em></p>

<p>“Those guys eat me for breakfast,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“It’s way easier to fuck them, though, because that’s what they do all the time,” Ha-joon said. “Working out increases your testosterone and sex drive.”</p>

<p>“Oh, please, what hope do ordinary fags have?” Ben said. “Masc4masc are sluts for muscles. They don’t drool at mortal beings.”</p>

<p>“It’s not like they don’t have a personality,” Mayume said. “They had one – or at least used to. But they don’t need it anymore.”</p>

<p>“I can confirm,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>Will chuckled. Ben wasn’t sure if out of agreement or awkwardness.</p>

<p><em>Pretty privilege was real for both sexes</em>. Will always gave free entry to hot influencers. Ben was sure that Will was also on the receiving end of this exchange.</p>

<p>But playing it cool – did it even work anymore?</p>

<p><em>I didn’t want to seem desperate</em>. Yet muscle worship was invented by gym gays.</p>

<p>“It’s a fine balance between ignoring their barks and chasing their tail,” Will said. “Every time you throw them a bone, take two steps back.”</p>

<p>“Let them come to you,” Ha-joon said. “Beefcakes love being destroyed by a skinny dom.”</p>

<p>“Oh, please,” Ben said. “’Opposites attract’ is bullshit. Ask any psychologist.”</p>

<p>“Well,” Ha-joon said, “it’s only because they’re hung.”</p>

<p><em>So many gay couples looked and acted the same. They even sought the same ethnicity</em>.</p>

<p>As a child, Ben’s parents had dressed him and his twin in identical clothing. The brothers had shared a room and afterschool activities. Now, Ben had relocated to the country on Earth that resembled his home the least. </p>

<p>“All my relationships have been with guys from other continents,” Will said.</p>

<p>“In that case, I’d drink too,” Ha-joon said, and grabbed Will’s vodka.</p>

<p>“But would you date them?” Ben asked.</p>

<p>Ha-joon gulped before he replied.</p>

<p>“I’d fuck me,” he said. “I’d fuck me hard.”</p>

<p>“You would?” Mayume asked.</p>

<p>“Yeah. I jerk off in front of the mirror.”</p>

<p>“Do you also watch your reflection while having sex?” Ben asked, recalling Cal.</p>

<p>“And the video after.”</p>

<p>“Is that why you made out with two other Koreans at the same time during Pride?” Will laughed.</p>

<p>Ha-joon snickered.</p>

<p>“At least I kept my shirt on.”</p>

<p>Twilight fell on the Chiyoda district. Ben peeked at Will, recalling his naked torso, and how his boy toys tended to be shorter than him.</p>

<p>“So you’re not attracted to yourself?” Ben asked.</p>

<p>Will raised his brows.</p>

<p>“He prefers courtesy to abs,” Ha-joon sniggered.</p>

<p>“Do you, though?” Ben asked.</p>

<p>Will smiled in lieu of an answer.</p>

<p>“Does Stephen know you’re back?” he asked.</p>

<p>“He unfollowed me a year ago,” Ben said.</p>

<p>“Better than stalking,” Ha-joon said, and eyed Mayume.</p>

<p>“Mind your own business, sir,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>A Japanese guy walked by. He had black bangs with pink highlights, and two strands of hair spiked like devil horns. His white t-shirt was too small on him, his army pants were too wide, and his chunky sneakers elevated his stature. This was complemented by acne cheeks, black headphones, a lip piercing, silver rings, a rusty yellow purse, and a studded emo belt hanging loose over his pants.</p>

<p><em>I wanted to be him.</em></p>

<p>Japan was the only place on Earth where one could see lads like him. Even straight guys sported nail polish while holding hands with their girlfriend.</p>

<p>“They just want to be fucked, period,” Ha-joon said. “Every dude you see.”</p>

<p><em>Masc and mortals</em>. Ben wished to hide under the blanket, and never return to dating.</p>

<p>“I’d fuck me so hard,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>As the sky darkened, the foursome headed to the train station.</p>

<p>“Cake alert,” Ben said, and jerked his head at a jogger with a bouncing rear.</p>

<h2 id="the-schools-closed-club">The School’s Closed Club</h2>

<p>The second day of school felt endless. Not because it was boring – it involved long reading passages, and a challenging vocabulary. Sitting next to Ben, Kacie raced through the passages faster than anyone else.</p>

<p>Ben continued to study the students instead. Danyil was another sun-kissed, sky-eyed European, with a brow piercing and a perpetual bandana. Alain dressed like an English lit Oxbridge lad. Shin had a lot of freckles, and wore baggy jeans with a grandpa vest. He avoided conversations with everyone.</p>

<p>Then the classroom started to shake. The students all glanced at each other in realization, while the teacher continued talking without noticing the earthquake.</p>

<p>During recess, after Ben made small talk with some students, Nathan continued to be the only one to exhibit a desire for chatting. His eager speech raised a smile on Ben’s face, as opposed to other guys from school he’d been noticing, whose divine bone structure tempted him. Yet Nathan rushed home every day after class to work.</p>

<p>The cold lack of socializing in Ben’s class took him by surprise, until he realized: the friends he had made during his trip, and his tourist roommates from the share house, wanted to meet people. Hence, he had befriended them in an instant. In an intermediate class, however, everyone was already settled into their routine.</p>

<p><em>Maybe this explained why Japanese people barely hung out with their friends</em>, Ben thought. <em>They were just deep in their own world.</em></p>

<p>As an introvert, he had done the same in university. As an ambivert, he yearned to develop long-term friendships with the students.</p>

<p><em>Perhaps I should take this as a slow-burn challenge.</em></p>

<p>At the end of each day, the students wiped their desks, and went to their separate paths. Even at a school for Caucasians, Ben had to duck under passageways.</p>

<p>The afternoon and evening were spent in bed, looking for apartments and trying to forget that ‘sporty for sporty’ gods existed. His mind resisted this image, yet his body was ravenous.</p>

<p>*</p>

<p>The next day, Ben began to sink into the school drill. Eternal classes; frequent glancing at his watch; talking to the other students about the material and everyday life.</p>

<p>“I can’t sit next to Kacie again, she stresses me out,” he said and sat next to Nathan.</p>

<p>Based on his hair and skin, Ben had assumed Nathan was younger than him. He turned out to be a few years older.</p>

<p>He held a master’s degree in physics. When Ben asked him not to rest his phone on his lap, Nathan explained the safety of such radiation like a charismatic rhetorician.</p>

<p>His Japanese was a bit slow when they paired in class. They did a short presentation together. Everyone read their script off their iPad, while Ben freaked out, strayed from his, and blurted the topic as if to his Japanese friends.</p>

<p>He continued to examine his eye level when speaking to other guys. Some appeared to match his stature. Others wore shorts that revealed soccer thighs. No one seemed interested in visiting a museum exhibition with him, when he suggested this after class. So instead, he attended a party planning meeting.</p>

<p>For the first time since COVID, the school was throwing a summer party. It would happen the day after Ben was planning to move into a new apartment. But he was determined to meet more and more students.</p>

<p>The meeting was held by the American IT guy, who stood two meters tall. Ben volunteered to be the MC.</p>

<p><em>If people got to know me, I would get to know them</em>.</p>

<p>Then a staff member mentioned that there were five other Israelis at school. Three guys and three girls, including Ben. Flabbergasted, he asked to be introduced to them next week.</p>

<p>Excited by the social prospects of the near future, he returned elated to his share house, and wolfed down natto rice with tofu and bean sprouts. Life felt good at this moment, as a student about to meet other international students in a big city.</p>

<h2 id="public-sex-gone-wrong">Public Sex Gone Wrong</h2>

<p><em>The morning after Stephen and I met, we attended Tokyo Pride parade. My ears were no longer ringing.</em></p>

<p><em>We walked alongside dozens of other participators. Bystanders cheered and applauded. I waved at them, incapable of erasing the smile on my face. It was the happiest atmosphere I’d revelled in.</em></p>

<p><em>“This is my first pride without any hatred,” Stephen remarked, having attended several in England.</em></p>

<p><em>There were security guards and police officers, yet no need for them. Everything was orderly. I’d had a feeling Japan would be the safest place to dip one’s toes into a queer celebration.</em></p>

<p><em>Still, most of the participators seemed straight. No doubt they meant well – but it did feel invasive.</em></p>

<p><em>After a short and inspiring hour, our group finished circling Shibuya and Harajuku. I was sad to return to Yoyogi Park. I felt as high as last night.</em></p>

<p><em>Soon enough, Stephen had to leave, and I found myself alone again in an endless crowd.</em></p>

<p><em>Like yesterday’s Pride festival, no one else appeared solitary. I struggled to make conversation.</em></p>

<p><em>So I snuck into another parading group, seeking to retaste the sugar from mere hours ago. A couple was holding a sign that read “love” in Japanese, English, and Hebrew.</em></p>

<p><em>They were visiting from Tel Aviv. We chatted for half an hour. Yet didn’t seem eager to go out tonight.</em></p>

<p><em>As my spirit fell, my phone beeped.</em></p>

<p><em>“Are you at pride?” a Dutch friend texted. “I’m on my way!”</em></p>

<p><em>We met in Yoyogi. I filled her in on last night: how I had dipped my toes into dancing, felt awkward, closed my eyes, and let go, so much that people had thought I was on drugs.</em></p>

<p><em>“Wait, so, you weren’t high?” she asked.</em></p>

<p><em>“No! I was just having fun.”</em></p>

<p><em>“You were high on life, then.”</em></p>

<p><em>I did not expect to hear this phrase again, let alone to describe me.</em></p>

<p><em>We continued to a standing bar in Shibuya. At night, we ran around the Scramble, revelling in the world’s busiest pedestrian crossing. The moon was shining in-between skyscrapers.</em></p>

<p><em>Longing to return to the dance floor, however, I prepared for round two in ni-chome.</em>  </p>

<p><em>This time, I danced in three different clubs. Sunday proved less crowded than Saturday.</em></p>

<p><em>The first guy I hit on was a shy Egyptian student who was standing in a corner. He had a great smile, despite his desire to “fix” his teeth.</em></p>

<p><em>After dancing and flirting for quite some time, he started pointing at all the guys he fancied. His type – hyper-masculine Middle Eastern – made me pale like vanilla next to zaatar.</em></p>

<p><em>“I miss my fuck buddies from Egypt,” he said.</em></p>

<p><em>He couldn’t bring himself to approach any zaatar. I encouraged him to try. Yet his attempt did not bear fruit.</em></p>

<p><em>“Oh well, he just lost twenty-one centimetres,” he grinned and shuffled through the crowd.</em></p>

<p><em>“What?” I exclaimed. Yet he was gone.</em></p>

<p><em>Alone at the heart of a throng, I tried to dance and move on. Alcohol, music, PDA, and gloom – no more ingredients were necessary to make leftover food. Especially in a culture whose locals never partied on their own.</em></p>

<p><em>I went through the same process of feeling self-conscious, peeping at couples, loosening up, and closing my eyes. Once again, I let go.</em></p>

<p><em>Music was pulsating in my ears. Heat condensed on my neck and warmed my body all the way to my bones. I felt like I was in another world: not on Earth, where things were complicated, but on a planet teeming with dim bodies and pop songs.</em></p>

<p><em>The next venue, less busy but featuring poles, cooked more of the same. A blond guy, seemingly in his thirties, hit on me. Uninterested, I returned to the former club, exchanged a few bland words with the student, and continued dancing.</em></p>

<p><em>My throat started to hurt from screaming lyrics. My stomach became sore from hip movements. Yet even pain mattered little as I jumped to the beat of the song. I kept imagining myself from above, squashed inside a dark club with eyes shut, dancing and laughing. Nothing about this felt emblematic of my existence.</em></p>

<p><em>But the night led me nowhere. No one appeared to enjoy my company. Only a mixed-gender group, which I crashed into.</em></p>

<p><em>Too bad Stephen couldn’t come.</em></p>

<p><em>I watched a go-go boy show for the first time. A Japanese girl next to me kept giggling in embarrassment. We ran jokes throughout the deafening songs.</em></p>

<p><em>Finally, I left the third and final club, solitary and doleful. As I ambled through the quiet alleys of ni-chome in the dead of night, I couldn’t help but wonder. Was this real life? Could it really feel this high and low?</em></p>

<p><em>The streets grew empty, and so did my heart, after feeling on top of the world.</em></p>

<p><em>Facing multiple rejections, my self-esteem had sagged like a cheese cake. No matter how highly I thought of myself, one glance at Grindr spat on that. One night at a gay club threw it to the trash.</em></p>

<p><em>Was I really that ugly? They guys I wanted never even glanced at me.</em></p>

<p><em>I wasn’t sure whether to laugh or cry.</em></p>

<p><em>Then someone called me. The blond guy, who turned out to be Australian. He was wobbling and slurring, until he started to touch me.</em></p>

<p><em>We found a deserted spot. He kneeled. I closed my eyes and tried to convince myself that this was pleasuring. Then I noticed a police officer move out of the corner of my eye.</em></p>

<p><em>I shut it again. Better to live on the fun planet.</em></p>

<p><em>The recipe ended as fast as it began. A bittersweet sauce, and a walk of shame. I didn’t even want to know the Australian’s name or age.</em></p>

<p><em>I lumbered in exhaustion back to my hotel, when three police officers on bikes ambushed me out of nowhere.</em></p>

<p><em>“Did you drink?” they asked in English.</em></p>

<p><em>I was so worried about getting into trouble, that I grew wide awake.</em></p>

<p><em>“I apologize sincerely,” I bowed and repeated in formal Japanese.</em></p>

<p><em>They searched my body for drugs, examining every pocket, the inside of my socks, my bag, and my wallet. It was one of the only times when I was out and about in Japan without my passport.</em></p>

<p><em>The officers rebuked me – the law forced tourists to carry passports with them at all times – but my ID and hotel card sufficed. They released me without punishment or warning.</em></p>

<p><em>I couldn’t recall seeing them patrol the area last night.</em></p>

<p><em>It was ironic how vapid my life had used to be. Israel had plunged me to rock bottom in a close-minded society; Japan offered me unique and tolerant feasts. I was embarking on adventures I’d never dared to pursue. Not even as a teenager and a university student had I felt such a kick.</em></p>

<p><em>Yet even here, one thing stayed universal. No matter the cuisine, taste buds salivated for only one kind of meal.</em></p>

<p><em>I love dessert, I thought in bed, dreaming about lollipops and peaches. But ultimately, I missed the main dish.</em></p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/UvfNmXbVHi4" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="satbc" /><category term="chiyoda" /><category term="ni-chome" /><category term="shin-okubo" /><category term="tokyo-pride" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I felt it was time to call it a night. I had never felt so invisible in my entire life.” Sex and the City (season 1, episode 2)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Land of Organised Chaos</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/08/18/the-land-of-organised-chaos-%E7%B5%84%E7%B9%94%E7%9A%84%E6%B7%B7%E6%B2%8C%E3%81%AE%E5%9B%BD.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Land of Organised Chaos" /><published>2024-08-18T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-08-18T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/08/18/the-land-of-organised-chaos-%E7%B5%84%E7%B9%94%E7%9A%84%E6%B7%B7%E6%B2%8C%E3%81%AE%E5%9B%BD</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/08/18/the-land-of-organised-chaos-%E7%B5%84%E7%B9%94%E7%9A%84%E6%B7%B7%E6%B2%8C%E3%81%AE%E5%9B%BD.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“To act, to create, to struggle against facts, to overcome them or be overthrown by them, all human health and joy consists in that!”</p>

  <p>“A mere way of diverting one’s self,” murmured the other.</p>

  <p>“Well! I prefer diverting myself. As one must die, I would rather die of passion than boredom!”</p>

  <p>They both laughed, this reminded them of their old discussions at college.</p>

  <p>Emile Zola, “The Ladies’ Paradise”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>In this chapter, I…</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Travel to Shikoku for five eventful days</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Reunite with friends, visit Cat Island, and indulge on my favourite Japanese dish</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Travel to crowded, coastal cities at risk of tsunami from Japan’s first-ever megaquake alert</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Attend Matsuyama Yakyu-ken Odori festival, Kochi Yosakoi festival, and Tokushima Awa Odori festival</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Camp for the first time, on the top of a mountain</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Realise Japan epitomises organised chaos</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h2 id="8-august-2024">8 August 2024</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>19:50-08:05 Busta Shinjuku bus terminal to Dogo Onsen station night bus</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Matsuyama castle</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>13:00-14:00 Matsuyama station to Iyo-Nagahama station local train, 14:30-15:05 Nagahama port to Aoshima port ferry</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Aoshima island (1h)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>16:15-16:50 Aoshima port to Nagahama port ferry, 17:40-18:40 Iyo-Nagahama station to Matsuyama station local train</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="matsuyama">Matsuyama</h3>

<p>I slept five hours, waking every half an hour or so. I loathed night buses in Japan.</p>

<p>At 8:00, I arrived at Dogo Onsen. It felt so good to leave stormy Tokyo for round three in sunny Shikoku.</p>

<p>I remembered where my hostel from last time was, dropped my luggage there, and went to meet Zaku, a local friend, at 8:30. I was already tired and ravenous.</p>

<p>But it felt great to be back in Matsuyama, back in the countryside, back with a friend, back in travel mode. The steam train outside Dogo Onsen station, the old clock… crickets and the occasional car or tram. It was quiet.</p>

<p>I already saw visitors walking around in yukata. All the shops and services were closed at this hour. Every elderly person was wearing a mask.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360583/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0615-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0616-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0618-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Zaku and I decided to visit Cat Island later today. To kill time until the only ferry, we went to Matsuyama castle. As we climbed up the stairs, he became a puddle. </p>

<p>“Wait,” I said. “It’s not humid. I’m not sweating!”</p>

<p>The air was light and clean. Tokyo had made me forget such conditions existed.  </p>

<p>Just like in Osaka, we’d chatted in front of the castle without bothering to enter it. Several hours passed like this, until I found onigiri at 7/11 that were new to me. I recalled how traveling constantly flung new stimuli at you, even as small as different food at the same store. My cultural shocks during one month of living in Tokyo had been daily, but encompassed apartment-hunting, Japanese ways of doing things, and social interactions.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0622-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0624-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0626-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<h3 id="aoshima">Aoshima</h3>

<p>We took the train from Matsuyama station south. When was my last time riding a one-car local train? It snailed down the western coast of Shikoku, revealing a beautiful view of the ocean. Small towns with traditional roofs and greenery filled the train’s windows. I napped during most of the ride with my head slumped forwards, and woke with a stiff neck.</p>

<p>The station we arrived at was one of those tiny, rural stops with a defunct ticket gate and a seemingly abandoned interior that featured dusty pillows and benches. The ferry terminal was a one-minute walk.</p>

<p>“The air is so clean!” I marvelled.</p>

<p>We bought tickets inside the boat and wrote down our names, place of residence, and round-trip details. There were barely five other passengers.</p>

<p>“That’s a relief,” we both said. The ferry operated only twice a day, and held up to 34 people. Today was the height of summer vacation and festival season, so we were worried about capacity.</p>

<p>Five people lived on Aoshima, probably the smallest island I’d visited. A dozen cats or so were roaming the feeding station, half of them dishevelled and unkempt, with scary bags underneath their eyes and snot that was making them wheeze.</p>

<p>I’d assumed there would be hundreds of them. They quickly turned out a disappointment. The small shrine was more interesting, decorated with corals. Yet the highlight was the view of some of the clearest water and sky I’d seen. The island looked perfect with the clouds resting directly in front of its traditional homes. Most of the latter were abandoned and overgrown with ivy.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0635-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360606/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0639-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0646-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0648-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0653-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0654-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0669-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0674-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0672-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>On the ferry back, everyone’s phones alerted of an earthquake. A 7.1 in Miyazaki prefecture. I didn’t feel anything.</p>

<p>This being the countryside, we waited for a whole hour for the infrequent train back. Today was slow and mild; all according to plan. I was exhausted from a night of no sleep, and saved all my intense activities for tomorrow onwards.</p>

<p>Yet instead of going to bed early, a Ukrainian friend called me, crying. Someone who had relocated to Japan around the same time as me and hated it so much, that she wanted to leave it.</p>

<p>Both of us had hailed here from countries currently torn by war, so it was difficult to entertain the notion that Japan was worse. Her complaints ranged from the toxic working culture, to the alienated social life, and the racist bureaucracy.</p>

<p>“I miss being hugged,” she lamented.</p>

<p>After a couple of hours like this, I discovered that my futon was a firm mattress, while the pillow was the traditional variant filled with buckwheat. I liked it.</p>

<p><strong>Today’s highlights:</strong> returning to the countryside; the one-car train ride; the view from Aoshima.</p>

<h2 id="9-august-2024">9 August 2024</h2>

<ul>
  <li>18:00-21:00 Matsuyama Yakyu-ken Odori festival</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="japans-first-megaquake-alert">Japan’s First Megaquake Alert</h3>

<p>I barely slept. Someone had been coughing night and morning in my dorm. At 8:30, I gave up on slumber. A friend from Kochi informed me of a new Nankai Trough earthquake warning for the next 2-3 days.</p>

<p>It was Japan’s first-ever mega-quake alert, and I was right in the danger zone. The tsunami warning had already been lifted, yet my next few days would be spent attending festivals in coastal cities alongside hundreds of thousands of people.</p>

<p>Great.</p>

<p>I lay puzzled and concerned in bed. This mega-quake could be the worst in Japan’s history. Yet I’d already survived a 7.5 in April, in Taipei. Back then, an aftershock had been projected to occur over the next 2-3 days as well. In the end, countless of aftershocks had happened 2-3 weeks later.</p>

<p>I rushed to the tourist information center to ask for their advice.</p>

<p>“Don’t worry,” they urged me. “It’s fine.”</p>

<p>Maybe Japanese people were used to earthquake alerts, the same way Israelis didn’t let missiles ruin their plans. They told me to go and simply evacuate with everyone if anything happened.</p>

<p>Yet the potential stampede made my friend from Kochi change his mind about tomorrow’s festival. I’d attend it alone.</p>

<p>Upon returning to my hostel, I met an Irish guy from my dorm who would also attend Matsuyama’s festival today and Kochi’s tomorrow. He was an ALT from Wakkanai who had quit after one year, and was now traveling all the way to Kyushu before his return home.</p>

<p>Then I met Zaku in Okaido station. We found the best spot to view tonight’s festival, at the intersection of Okaido and Gintengai.</p>

<p>No one was there.</p>

<p>It was 11:30, and no one had secured a spot yet. So we went souvenir shopping at Mitsukoshi.</p>

<p>When we returned to the coveted spot an hour later, it was still empty. Okaido shopping arcade was quiet. There were very few people out and about.</p>

<p>So we returned to the souvenir street for a 100-yen mikan juice and Imabari towel shop. The best towels in Japan – but far out of budget for me.</p>

<p>At 13:30, the intersection was still empty. We ate a long lunch at Hanamaru Udon, discussing cultural differences among Asian countries, and then among Europeans. He hadn’t realized that white people also had different cultures.</p>

<p>At 15:30, the intersection was still empty.</p>

<p>What was this? Where was everyone? I was used to showing up in the morning, securing a spot, and waiting all day long with the accumulating crowd until the evening.</p>

<p>We rested by the intersection to no end. An old man showed up with a tiny foldable chair. He was the only attendee.</p>

<p>At 17:00, the police closed the road to traffic. No one else had secured a spot.</p>

<p>“The countryside is so boring,” I grouched. Zaku and I waited hours without talking much. I apologised for dragging him this early to the festival.</p>

<p>Everything was so small in the countryside, that running into familiar faces was not at all uncommon. Like the Irish guy.</p>

<h3 id="matsuyama-yakyu-ken-odori-festival">Matsuyama Yakyu-ken Odori Festival</h3>

<p>At 18:00, the festival began. Matsuyama was the birthplace of baseball in Japan, so this dance festival was supposed to celebrate it. The groups performed once inside the arcade and then left. Our location was used for passage.</p>

<p>We entered the arcade and joined the crowd, which was about 100-200 people.</p>

<p>The performances started off bad. They were boring, and lacked anything remotely related to baseball.</p>

<p>Gradually, they improved, with gorilla costumes and disabled people who wore sunglasses and suits. The unexpected wackiness reminded me of a Yokai festival in Osaka.</p>

<p>At 19:30, the performances ended. We walked to Shiroyama Park for part 2 of the program. It was my first time at a festival that changed locations.</p>

<p>Because of this and the sparse attendance, there was no reason to show up before the start time.</p>

<p>At the park, we watched the same groups perform the same routine on a stage. It was quite boring. After an hour, the performances ended, and staff members handed out towels.</p>

<p>The crowd walked to the front of the stage and learned a dance routine. Only Ehime prefecture could incorporate a towel-themed dance into a festival. I thoroughly enjoyed this.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0680-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360585/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0686-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0699-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At 21:00, the festival ended. I was wide awake with adrenaline. We took the tram back to Dogo Onsen and climbed to the foot onsen we’d visited last time. There was no water! But the view of Dogo Onsen, no longer undergoing renovations, was quaint.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0701-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0702-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0703-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>I lay in bed for two hours until I dozed off at midnight. The guy below my bunk kept chewing in bed, making weird noises, and slamming the door. To cap it all off, he talked in his sleep.</p>

<p><strong>Today’s highlights:</strong> the wacky bits of Matsuyama Yakyu-ken Odori festival; Dogo Onsen at night.</p>

<h2 id="10-august-2024">10 August 2024</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>11:37-14:07 Otemachi station to Hariyamabashi station bus</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Lunch @ Hirome Market</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Kochi Yosakoi information exchange center (30m)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>17:00-22:00 Kochi Yosakoi festival</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>I woke to silence. The hostel was empty. Where was everyone?</p>

<p>I checked the news. A small aftershock in Miyazaki, plus a 5.1 earthquake in Kanagawa. But no disaster.</p>

<p>Fearing another aftershock, I boarded my bus to Kochi (the usual awful seats, way too sunken in the back and low for my head), and left Matsuyama content. I had exhausted all that it had to offer.</p>

<p>The bus ride was gorgeous, though, through green valleys and ravines. I loved traveling in the countryside.</p>

<p>As soon as I alighted at Hariyamabashi, all hell broke loose.</p>

<h3 id="hirome-market">Hirome Market</h3>

<p>Kochi had turned from a snoozy small city to a colourful celebration of dance and music. The streets were alive with teams wearing elaborate costumes in various hues and prints. They wore headbands or hats and held naruko – Yosakoi festival’s signature percussion. Street food vendors lined every passageway, while crowds filled the space in-between.</p>

<p>At 15:00, the street outside Hirome Market was as crowded as it got. Performances were already in full force. The market itself was also bustling. I headed straight to the Katsuo no Tataki shop and got the biggest portion. My favourite dish in Japan, and a good enough reason to return to its least visited prefecture. I couldn’t find a table, though, until an old Japanese man who had finished eating insisted I sat in his stead.</p>

<p>The katsuo was as delicious as I’d remembered: like grilled sashimi. Charred, yet raw. The pinch of sea salt went a long way. The soy sauce ruined the fish, however, because it was the astringent yuzu that made the grilled flavour pop.</p>

<p>I noticed the only other foreigner around, and invited her to join me. She hesitated a bit, but acquiesced.</p>

<p>She was a Czech twentysomething on a working holiday in Japan, here to watch her friend perform at Yosakoi.</p>

<p>“Foreigners can perform?!” I exclaimed.</p>

<p>We had a nice lunch. “I have to go,” she said at 16:00. “I leave in 1.5 hours.”</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0723-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360605/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0720-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360594/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0722-1024x768.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<h3 id="kochi-yosakoi-festival">Kochi Yosakoi Festival</h3>

<p>Outside the market, a purple and orange group made my jaw drop.</p>

<p>Dozens of Japanese people were dancing and swinging naruko to upbeat J-pop. They beamed and moved in perfect unison, with gold jewelry on their face and enviable happi coats. As I followed them into the shopping arcade and squeezed between spectators and passersby along a narrow passageway, the full scale of the festival dawned on me.</p>

<p>Yosakoi was an energetic dance style that had originated in Kochi 71 years ago. It juxtaposed traditional dancing with modern music. Nowadays, 20,000 dancers participated in the festival, across hundreds of teams that performed simultaneously all over the city center.</p>

<p>Each team was led by a truck that transported gigantic speakers, so loud that their vicinity rumbled. Inside the truck, taiko drum players were sweating profusely, while singers stood on its roof. Every truck advanced slowly (slowly!) along the arcade, while its team was performing. Hundreds of Japanese dancers of all genders and ages performed in unison with naruko, whose wooden clanking rose above the speakers’ bass. Behind one team performed another team, and so on, like a conveyor belt of entertainment.</p>

<p>Seeing and hearing multiple teams at once inside the cramped arcade, where one could barely find a spot to stand or squeeze through the crowd to follow the team’s performance, reminded me how vibrant Japan was. The colours, the grins, the clanking, and the rumbling felt like the communal version of an urban arcade, where people played nigh-epileptic games alone.</p>

<p>The purple and orange team was by far my favourite. Their original song, costumes, and choreography were electrifying. I smiled as if seeing the sun for the first time. It was yet another moment on my travels that became instantly unforgettable. Not since Akita Kanto had a festival in Japan fascinated me so.</p>

<p>I followed this team for half an hour until the end of their performance, and resolved to sign up for participation next year with a group from Tokyo.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0714-1-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360585/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0726-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0740-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0742-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360596/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0763-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0768-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At 16:30, I entered the Yosakoi museum. Its explanations about the history of festival were hard to follow. But then I tried on a Yosakoi costume that was tragically not for sale.</p>

<p>Between 17:00-19:00, I walked around Kochi wowed. From shopping arcades to Chuo Park, where teams performed on a stage: one by one, their trucks treaded into the stage area, and parked right next to the crowd. The entire scene was both erratic and orderly at the same time. So many things could go wrong, yet nothing did.</p>

<p>Still, after an hour of this, the performances began to grow old. Some teams had picked slow songs and unappealing outfits, or barely used their naruko.</p>

<p>At 19:00, I settled at the park, exhausted from running amok. I heard Hebrew spoken right beside me, and met a middle-aged Israeli man with three toddlers. He was a blacksmith who lived with his Japanese wife in a forest on a mountain between Tottori and Okayama. Yosakoi was a first for them, but Tokushima Awa Odori festival was an annual tradition, which included camping. He wasn’t worried about a tsunami, and invited me to a specific spot in Tokushima two days from now.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0771-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0790-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0796-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0798-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0801-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0828-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0830-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0832-576x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360606/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0837-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>After touring the shopping arcades again and feeling disappointed by the performances, the festival ended at 22:00. I was relieved. Weariness and over-saturation had prevented it from dethroning Akita Kanto as my favourite festival in Japan. Only the electrifying teams had spoken to me.</p>

<p>So I walked for ten minutes to my accommodation, a run-down business hotel with plastic sheets and no elevator. I ran a hot bath, my first since volunteering at a temple near Fuji-san in January. Sitting cramped inside an ancient, square bathtub felt as snug as a hug.</p>

<p>But I couldn’t last long. My blood pressure dropped, so I left the bath, and went to sleep a little after midnight. Today was one of my best days of traveling.</p>

<p><strong>Today’s highlights:</strong> KATSUO NO TATAKI; Yosakoi Kochi festival; the hot bath.</p>

<h2 id="11-august-2024">11 August 2024</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Breakfast @ Hirome Market</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>11:30-12:00 Kochi Yosakoi festival</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>12:45-14:20 Kochi station to Osugi station local train (Dosan line)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Camping</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="hirome-market-1">Hirome Market</h3>

<p>I checked out at 10:30 and walked to Hirome Market. The tourist information center informed me that Yosakoi outfits could not be bought.</p>

<p>Tragic.</p>

<p>But applying to a team was possible, from May onwards. And apparently, Tokyo would host its own Yosakoi two weeks from now, in Yoyogi.</p>

<p>I ate katsuo no tataki for breakfast. The market was so teeming, that it took me several minutes to find a table. Moreover, I was the only foreigner.</p>

<p>A Japanese family invited me to sit at their table. They treated me to some of their food, which included my first whale meat. It was the superior version of fried chicken. Perfectly tender.</p>

<h3 id="kochi-yosakoi-festival-1">Kochi Yosakoi Festival</h3>

<p>I left with my stomach bursting and saw that the performances outside the market had begun. The first group I stumbled upon repeated yesterday’s immediate jaw drop. For half an hour, I followed their entire routine.</p>

<p>It was a female group led by male singers. They performed quickly and effortlessly to upbeat J-pop. The entire spectacle was so absorbing, that I couldn’t stop smiling. Maybe Yosakoi did deserve to tie Akita Kanto. The latter was a feat of individual strength, while the former was a celebration of communal effort.</p>

<p>I squeezed through crowds standing in tiny passageways as I followed the team through the shopping arcade, until I reached Chuo Park at 12:00. No performances here yet – and I ought to get going, anyway. At 12:00, I took the tram from Hariyamabashi to Kochi station.</p>

<p>Kochi was much more spirited than Matsuyama. Even the trams were themed with cartoons. They were bigger and featured better shading. But Kochi was a bit more humid, because it was a bigger city.</p>

<p>Unlike Matsuyama, which enjoyed more Korean and Chinese tourists than Japanese, the opposite was true here.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360605/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0843-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0845-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0858-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<h3 id="camping-in-kochi">Camping in Kochi</h3>

<p>I took the local train to Osugi station. Sam was already waiting for me at the car park.</p>

<p>“Sensei,” I grinned and gave him a long, tight hug. My first of this sort since leaving Israel.</p>

<p>He was an ALT from Australia who I’d met during my only night in Kochi on my first time. In typical Japanese fashion, the front of his car sported Pokémon and Mario Kart plushies.</p>

<p>We drove to the nearest gas station that was open on Sunday for forty minutes. After stocking up at Family Mart, we cooked dinner at his apartment. It was three times the size of mine.</p>

<p>It was also my first time experiencing sweat-inducing humidity on this trip to Shikoku.</p>

<p>Only the outdoors was airy and light. But what outdoors was here to be found: even the view from his building was breathtaking. An expansive green valley with a teal river and off-white rocks.</p>

<p>The air was so clean. The landscape was so picturesque. Everything was so serene.</p>

<p>It was dead quiet, but that was the point – no one was around to make a ruckus. Only a rare car made some noise.</p>

<p>The great outdoors, right on his doorstep.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360589/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0861-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We improvised dinner by frying rice with tofu and frozen vegetables. He was quite elaborate in his seasoning. I always threw in some sesame oil and soy sauce, while he added to this miso paste and other spices.</p>

<p>At 17:00, we finished cooking and packing camping essentials (a tent, pillows, blanket, mattress, etc.). We drove for forty minutes up the mountain by his village. I almost stumbled upon a permanent spiderweb by his parking space. The outlook from a bridge leading outside his village to the same valley was rightfully his favourite view. This was the Japanese countryside at its finest – lush mountains, crystal clear streams, pale rocks, and red bridges, all glittering in the summer breeze.</p>

<p>The road up the mountain was tricky. A bumpy, winding, one-lane ascend. A slice of nature I wouldn’t traverse alone an hour and a half before sunset.</p>

<p>“I hope we see a bear,” I said. “I’ve been to so many places in Japan infested by them, and talked to people who had just encountered one, but never managed to do it myself. I’m too unlucky in that sense.”</p>

<p>“Or lucky,” he laughed.</p>

<p>We crossed a small, hillside village that reminded me of Iya Valley’s Ochiai. The campground was located on top of a mountain that boasted a clear, 360-degree view of a mountain range, on par with the clouds.</p>

<p>There were already five tents or so. The Japanese campers who had pitched them were no amateurs. They were family-sized and included canopies, grills, firewood, full-blown feasts. We were the only ones late and ill-prepared. Our two-person tent, one chair, and konbini provisions paled in comparison with their charred meat and camembert cheese.</p>

<p>We greeted some of the families around us. They mostly ignored us. After my first camping attempt had gone horribly wrong (incidentally, in nearby Iya Valley), Sam possessed enough experience to pitch his new tent without reading any instructions.</p>

<p>Then it was time for sunset. We walked uphill to a cliff with a statue of a Buddha by the edge. It seemed like the calm version of the scary demon that stood on a clifftop temple in Shodoshima.</p>

<p>We found a bench and ate dinner. I began to shiver. It felt like fifteen degrees up here.</p>

<p>Soon, the other campers joined us. The sky began to blush, while the sinking sun dazzled us as it emerged from under a cloud.</p>

<p>「眩しい」the Japanese campers kept repeating.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360591/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0885-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360595/website_images/2024/08/C43BF698-1D48-47B0-BFD1-2DB594DC604C-770x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0894-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0899-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360602/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0907-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360596/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0919-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>We stayed by the Buddha well into dusk, long after they had descended to eat dinner. Deer were roaming on a hill. The lonesome meditator frozen in stone, high at a secluded spot like this – the purple sky – the cool air – the warm company of a friend in shoes similar to my own – I knew I wouldn’t forget this moment, before it even passed.</p>

<p>Then stars appeared. One by one, they adorned the night sky. With my new phone, I could finally photograph them.</p>

<p>Back by our tent, we finished our scant dinner, while the campers were hours into their feasts. The aromas that wafted in our direction gave us gear-envy. At some point, we heard food popping.</p>

<p>“Is that <em>popcorn</em>?” I said.</p>

<p>“Bastards,” Sam muttered. “They’re just showing off at this point.”</p>

<p>We shared a bottle of cheap wine that made me thankfully drowsy. Sunset was at 5:25, so an early bedtime was in order.</p>

<p>Everything about this evening was slow and quiet. Our dinner. Our conversations. Our long, voiceless staring into the horizon. The other campers’ seven-course meals. Life in nature felt unhurried and intimate. There was no rush, nothing to race to; no raging stimuli.</p>

<p>At 21:00, Sam and I retreated into our tent.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0925-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360589/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0926-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/76F0AAF4-F4EF-4C13-8991-8942D6BE6FBF-770x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360598/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0927-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360598/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0930-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360593/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0932-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><strong>Today’s highlights:</strong> KATSUO NO TATAKI; fried whale; Kochi Yosakoi festival; camping with Sam; the various landscapes I saw today; the clifftop Buddha at sunset; stargazing.</p>

<h2 id="12-august-2024">12 August 2024</h2>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>Camping, continued</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>12:37-14:50 Awa Ikeda station to Tokushima station local train (Tokushima line)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>18:00-22:00 Tokushima Awa Odori festival</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>22:40-7:40 Tokushima station to Busta Shinjuku bus terminal night bus</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h3 id="day-two-of-camping">Day Two of Camping</h3>

<p>We woke at 5:00. The other campers were already by the Buddha, preparing to watch the sunrise. It was cold and beautiful.</p>

<p>Then we fell asleep again in the tent. At 7:30, we nibbled some pastries for breakfast. I cancelled my bus from Kochi to Tokushima in order to spend more time with Sam.</p>

<p>When the tent grew too hot for us to stay in, I stepped outside and felt the grass under my feet. It was fresh and dewy. Walking around barefoot, I felt wild and primitive.</p>

<p>As the other campers were cooking elaborate breakfasts, I voiced my surprise at their aloofness. Japanese people, and Asians as a whole, tended to be polite and hospitable. Here, they barely deigned to say ‘good morning’ in return. I didn’t expect anyone to invite us over, even though it had happened to me in Asia more often than not, perhaps spoiling me by the end.</p>

<p>It occurred to me that past nights spent on top of Far Eastern mountains had gone the same way. I’d eaten small konbini meals while surrounded by well-equipped Asians, who hadn’t even glanced in my direction. As if tents and mountain huts had crossed the threshold of friendliness.</p>

<p>But I had all the company and food that I needed. My first time camping couldn’t have gone better.</p>

<p>Sam and I drove up the nearby mountain. A couple of snakes slithered away from his car. More Buddhas graced the observation point here.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360596/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0937-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360584/website_images/2024/08/635C9C5A-0205-4D9A-B557-75C967DEED2D-770x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360598/website_images/2024/08/E439920F-F00D-4C18-A34C-2A5BDFC68497-1024x768.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At 9:00, we started down the mountain. I checked the time for my limited express train to Tokushima. It would cost me, but I wouldn’t have made it to the bus anyway.</p>

<p>At 10:30, we arrived at Osugi station. The limited express had been cancelled due to a fallen tree.</p>

<p>Great. The only other way for me to reach Tokushima was to wait for the next limited express, three hours from now. Yet I was worried that it would be cancelled as well.</p>

<p>With the ongoing mega-quake alert, Sam had decided to skip the festival in Tokushima as well. I asked him to drive me one hour north to Awa Ikeda station, where I would take a local train. The gas could be even cheaper than the limited express.  </p>

<p>This also gave us more time together. He drove on a highway past Iya Valley. We crossed a dead tanooki on the way. Every digital sign on the road warned against the Nankai Trough megaquake.</p>

<p>“I’m really glad we did this,” I said at the station. “Especially with you.”</p>

<h3 id="tokushima-awa-odori-festival">Tokushima Awa Odori Festival</h3>

<p>After dozing off on the slow train to Tokushima, I reached it with ample time for the festival. There was already a battle for the coin lockers inside the station, and one performance at play. Two tourist information centers gave me the most amazing tips.</p>

<p>At 15:30, I secured a spot on the free viewing benches in Ryogokuhonmachi Stage. Only a third of the seats were taken. (In hindsight, it was a mistake to pick the center, because performances were liveliest at their beginning and end.)</p>

<p>Then I walked south and crossed Ryogokubashi Bridge. Tokushima was a nondescript city with a river and no attractions. The buildings were semi high. The crowd wasn’t here yet. The streets were half empty.</p>

<p>Shikoku was my first time encountering festivals that didn’t reward early attendance.</p>

<p>I searched all over the street food stands on the southern bank of the river, but couldn’t find the Lebanese falafel shop that sold chickpea donuts. Shame. I devoured a processed plate of takoyaki and returned to my seat at 16:30.</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360583/website_images/2024/08/IMG_0948-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At 18:00, the festival began.</p>

<p>Tokushima Awa Odori was the largest dance festival in Japan, in celebration of Obon. Over the course of its three days, it tended to attract close to one million attendees. Yet my first reaction was disappointment.</p>

<p>A simple procession with a dozen or so dancers. They progressed in a laboriously slow manner, raising and lowering their limbs with each step. Half of the underaged participators looked dead-eyed, pouting as if this was torture. The drum-and-flute melody was repetitive, while the moves were few and simple.</p>

<p>It was merely a bigger version of the Awa Odori I’d seen two weeks ago in Tokyo. Even the adults, most of their faces were stern.</p>

<p>Men tied bandanas around their noses like nasal cannulas. Women wore crescent straw hats and heeled geta.</p>

<p>「ア、ヤットサー！」 They chanted.</p>

<p>Then the performances rose in quantity and energy. Not enough to prevent me from getting bored an hour into this, though. They lacked variety and vigour.</p>

<p>A couple from Tokyo sat next to me and shared their food with me. An elaborate routine of a puppeteer reviving dancers caught my attention. We chatted until I left at 20:30 to check out other areas of the festival.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0952-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0956-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0960-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0974-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0976-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0978-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0986-1024x768.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Once I hit the streets, I noticed complete standstills in every square meter of the city center. Everywhere was packed with crowds, street food, and performances. Unlike the carefully rehearsed procession, there were small groups of dancers doing an improvised routine, surrounded by a circle of spectators.</p>

<p>I crossed Ryogokubashi Bridge and proceeded west, like the Israeli man had instructed me two days ago. No sooner had I squeezed through throngs of street food enjoyers on the narrow southern bank, full of food stands and shoppers, than I stumbled upon him and his family. We ran into each other face to face in this turmoil.</p>

<p>After a short talk, I continued to his recommendation. On the northern side of Shinmachibashi Bridge, Japanese hipsters with dreadlocks performed international songs to the beat of the festival’s melody. They sang Bob Marley as a crowd of attendees formed a circle of Awa Odori, trying to emulate the procession’s dance.</p>

<p>Instant déjà vu to Seoul’s Yeongdeunghoe (Lotus Lantern Festival). The same improvised circle and celebration. Everyone performed the dance routine quite badly while botching the chanting, until at some point they gave up and jumped on their spot. Bodies glistened with sweat and voices screamed with joy. It was like a traditional Japanese nightclub in the open air.</p>

<p>A man in a bikini; people eating yakisoba while sitting in the middle of the road; drums, flutes, percussion; red and yellow lanterns; kimono and jinbei; street food vendors; Southeast minors smoking cigarettes; people walking and shouting, laughing and drinking, eating and dancing; trash on the street; banjo. Somehow, this brouhaha was neither messy, nor dangerous. Chaotic, but controlled. Not by the police or some external force, yet on its own.</p>

<p>It felt like an urban yet historical rave. Japan always balanced ancient traditions with the new age.</p>

<p>I strolled around the city center, taking in this unbelievable commotion. The paid stages featured elevated platforms like in a sports stadium. But it was the atmosphere all over downtown that made sitting in one spot the entire night, not to mention paying for a seat, criminal.</p>

<p>What set Tokushima Awa Odori apart from other festivals – including local versions of Awa Odori, such as Tokyo’s – was its blurring of participator and viewer. The usual processions were overshadowed by the open-form dance groups, which encouraged the crowd to join them. The festival thus turned into a giant dance party, where the music and steps were centuries old.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0994-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_0996-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360586/website_images/2024/08/IMG_1002-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_1006-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360585/website_images/2024/08/IMG_1011-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/IMG_1017-768x1024.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At 22:00, the festival ended. It was hard to believe that my third time in Shikoku had come to a close; that so many sights and experiences were a product of five days alone. It was hard to believe that I would be back in a scorching metropolis tomorrow, not traveling but running errands for my relocation.</p>

<p>I took my night bus back to Tokyo, which was diabolical. No free-standing seats, sockets, toilet, nor Wi-Fi. It was just a regular bus.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I managed to sleep between six to seven hours. With frequent awakenings, but still. Before my trip, I had never managed to fall asleep on a seat. Even with the help of melatonin. Since then, my body had adjusted to unfamiliar and uncomfortable situations like this, and changed its habits. It felt good to know that I could overcome years-long difficulties, whether emotional or physical, and improve my body and spirit.</p>

<p><strong>Today’s highlights:</strong> the dewy grass; long drives with Sam; Tokushima Awa Odori festival.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w3zjXDlG9Ss" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="a-resident-of-japan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“To act, to create, to struggle against facts, to overcome them or be overthrown by them, all human health and joy consists in that!” “A mere way of diverting one’s self,” murmured the other. “Well! I prefer diverting myself. As one must die, I would rather die of passion than boredom!” They both laughed, this reminded them of their old discussions at college. Emile Zola, “The Ladies’ Paradise”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chapter 1: Have You Ever Made Love?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/15/chapter-1-have-you-ever-made-love-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0-%E6%84%9B%E3%82%92%E3%81%97%E3%81%9F%E3%81%93%E3%81%A8%E3%81%8C%E3%81%82%E3%82%8B.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chapter 1: Have You Ever Made Love?" /><published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-07-15T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/15/chapter-1-have-you-ever-made-love-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0%E3%83%BB%E6%84%9B%E3%82%92%E3%81%97%E3%81%9F%E3%81%93%E3%81%A8%E3%81%8C%E3%81%82%E3%82%8B%EF%BC%9F</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/15/chapter-1-have-you-ever-made-love-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0-%E6%84%9B%E3%82%92%E3%81%97%E3%81%9F%E3%81%93%E3%81%A8%E3%81%8C%E3%81%82%E3%82%8B.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>“Wait – have you ever been in love?”</p>

  <p>Sex and the City (season 1, episode 1)</p>
</blockquote>

<h2 id="you-are-what-you-love">You Are What You Love</h2>

<p>Once upon a time, in the most populated city on Earth, a boy met a boy.</p>

<p>Ben had just relocated to Tokyo. He had bangs, glasses, a stubble, and what people described as a ‘good boy’ face. Countless languages and ethnicities graced his new surroundings, in addition to fast and precise service. His residence card was created swiftly, while his luggage was already waiting by the baggage carousel.</p>

<p>“Please be careful” was being repeated incessantly.</p>

<p>He accidentally took the wrong train to the city. With twenty-three special wards, twenty-six sub-cities, five towns, and eight villages – forty-six municipalities, each with its own government – plus four other sub-prefectures, Tokyo was less of a city, and more of a monster.</p>

<p>It was as if dozens of cities had banded together to form an urban behemoth that rivalled states. The Skytree was the world’s tallest tower, Shibuya was the world’s busiest pedestrian crossing, and Shinjuku was the world’s busiest transport hub. Among the latter’s twelve lines, three million passengers rode just the Yamanote, which circled central Tokyo, every day.</p>

<p><em>That wasn’t even the half of it</em>, Ben said to no one in particular. <em>Try memorizing Tokyo’s sixty train lines and nine hundred stations.</em></p>

<p>Tokyo was dark, drizzling, hot, windy, and humid. Dragging two suitcases heavier than Ben nearly killed him. Then his new flatmate, a professional wrestler, carried them up for him.</p>

<p>The wrestler was as strong as he was friendly. Another bodybuilder wrestler was three times wider than him.</p>

<p>There was a shoe rack at the entrance and a heated bidet. Paper-thin walls and a deflated mattress. An unstoppable, hours-long chat with the international flatmates raised Ben’s spirits.</p>

<p>Forty million people inhabited The Greater Tokyo Area, more than four times the population of New York City. Commuters from other prefectures and tourists from all over the globe added a few millions to this. More than 600,000 of the residents were foreign, with practically every nationality counted for. 6,300 people lived in one square kilometre. If 10% of them were queer, 630 of them were at a walking distance.</p>

<p><em>No matter the time or sexual orientation</em>, <em>in Tokyo, one could always find a date</em>.</p>

<p>For thousands of years, queer people had struggled to pursue each other due to dread and secrecy. The twenty-first century was the first time in history where they could easily embrace the same sex.</p>

<p>In fact, it got so easy, that phone apps revealed their distance from each other in meters. They could see their physical proximity, send a message, and meet right there and then to fulfil God’s plan for the human derriere.</p>

<p>And they did so religiously. They exchanged photos, digits, girth, length, and inquired after each other’s preferences in bed. If the inventory checked all the boxes, they came together for some horizontal refreshment – or as the Japanese called it, a <em>rest</em>.</p>

<p>After this, they never met again.</p>

<p>They knew the other person was out there. Their faces (or torsos) re-appeared on their digital grid. They watched each other’s stories on Instagram, and reacted with a like or a message once every hunting season. Then they ignored the other person’s roar.</p>

<p>Having sightseen Tokyo last year, Ben knew what he was getting himself into, and who would be there for him. He chewed on this in a restaurant where conveyor belts transported sushi.</p>

<p>“I just don’t get it,” he said. “When did we enter the Age of Entitlement? People ask for fair treatment, and stab you in the ass.”</p>

<p>“Forget Reason, it’s the Age of Treason,” Mayume said. “People do what they want. If someone complains about it, they just block them.”</p>

<p>Ben chuckled. “By people, you mean you?”</p>

<p>“No, I just ignore them.”</p>

<p><em>Typical local</em>. Skinny, shy, and strife-avoidant: all the S’s you needed for capital S sex. Mayume had anime-bleached hair, a ‘little boy’ face, and oversized, graphic clothes that obscured his bony frame.</p>

<p>It took Ben a second to recall the lay of this land. Whether the suffocating insistence on harmony, or conveyor belt sushi. Relationships and restaurants came with rulebooks: you took chopsticks from a box, poured soy sauce into a small dish, brewed green tea using a powder and a hot water dispenser, served yourself pickled ginger, ordered using a tablet, and always ate the sushi in one bite.</p>

<p>“What’s the big deal?” Ha-joon said in response to Ben’s grouching. “You have fun, until you don’t. Then you move on. It’s not like you owe them anything.”</p>

<p><em>Ha-joon was as slick as his monolids.</em> He had perky, razor-sharp bangs, a ‘resting bitch’ face, and a plain, tight T-shirt that showed off his athletic physique.</p>

<p>“So you automatically reject any mess,” Ben said, “even if it might lead to treasure.”</p>

<p>“I don’t want any shit in my life,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“And if you find the real thing,” Mayume said, “it won’t reek.”</p>

<p>“So basically, it’s one-night stands, or saving yourself for marriage,” Ben said.</p>

<p>Apart from the whooshing of plates on conveyor belts, silence fell on the table.</p>

<p>“You talk about very serious things,” a thick Asian-European accent, who had listened quietly so far, said.</p>

<p>Ben flustered.</p>

<p>“That is why you need both,” the voice continued. “Open relationships allow you to get whatever you need.”</p>

<p><em>Willem was a Tokyo trailblazer</em>. He worked days at a hospital and nights at a club. His boyfriend lived abroad, so they hooked up with strangers during their time apart.</p>

<p>Even when sitting at a table, Will commanded the room’s attention. Taller than everyone around him, he wore dark, designer streetwear and silver jewelry. He had a ‘fashion model’ face, the kind that brightened a room when smiling, or came off as mysterious when not.</p>

<p>His English was magnetically slow, more eloquent than a native speaker’s. Ben always forgot Will’s Asian name.</p>

<p>“But then what’s the difference?” Ben asked. “You’re not committing to love, to sex, to anything, just to not committing.”</p>

<p>“To not committing,” Ha-joon raised his cup of tea and toasted with Mayume.</p>

<p>Ben frowned at this, while Will smiled softly.</p>

<p>“Oh, please, the right guy is bullshit,” Ha-joon said. “Haven’t you learned anything?”</p>

<p>“So what, you think love can never happen?” Mayume recoiled. “That it’s just for women? Not for gays?”</p>

<p>“Let me know when you find it,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>“You will,” Will said. “And then you will see the difference between sleeping with a stranger, and someone you love.”</p>

<p>“But I don’t know what it feels like to make love,” Ben muttered.</p>

<p>Silence again.</p>

<p>“I came close to, but I didn’t know it at the time,” he said. “So I never got to say ‘I love you’.”</p>

<p>“Oh, you have to tell them!” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“No way,” Ben said. “I’m trying this new thing where I have self-respect.”</p>

<p>“To self-respect,” Ha-joon toasted.</p>

<p>“It’s okay, I’ll just go with the other option,” Ben said. “Besides, years of writing complex philosophical fiction have prepared me for my greatest topic yet,” he added. “Gay sex.”</p>

<p>“Now that’s a tough nut to crack,” Mayume said.</p>

<p>“Good thing we have two,” Will said.</p>

<p>“One for fucking, and one for liking?” Ha-joon laughed. “The best of both sexy worlds.”</p>

<p>“So you never sleep with the same hookup twice?” Ben asked Will.</p>

<p>Will smiled in lieu of an answer.</p>

<p>More sushi arrived per the foursome’s orders. It was like a train set game, except with enthusiastic Japanese voices issuing from a tablet, and an endless supply of dead seafood. Ben stacked his empty plates and calculated his accumulating bill according to each plate’s colour.</p>

<p>“Seriously though, the moment you dislike something about someone…” he began.</p>

<p>Mayume put down his chopsticks and imitated waving.</p>

<p>“Bye!” he said. “Have a good life.”</p>

<p>The restaurant’s tablet announced incoming sushi. Ben fetched the cucumber rolls and sighed.</p>

<p>“Shouldn’t advancements in communication advance our communication?”</p>

<p><em>Welcome to the Glass Age</em>. It was just like the Stone Age, where hunter-gatherers had roamed free, and done whatever they wanted in nature and with each other, without being tied down like farmers. Except now, they did it with a phone in hand.</p>

<p>The glass that coated phone screens was see-through in the way that technology allowed us to share more of ourselves. It was touchable in a way that meant someone special was a mere tap away. It was reflective, so it confronted us with our real face. And it stood for Gays who Love Ass.</p>

<p><em>So why did it turn us into assholes instead?</em></p>

<p>“You are what you love,” Ha-joon said.</p>

<p>In the era of social media and dating apps, pictures superseded personalities, and an infinite dating pool burned to death all the fish in the ocean. It was like global warming, if coal was semen.</p>

<p>Gay dating had never been this accessible. Hormones raged at the speed of Wi-Fi and turned it lightning-fast. Some gays met complete strangers after three sentences.</p>

<p>“Looking for fun?”</p>

<p>“Top or bottom?”</p>

<p>“Can you host?”</p>

<p>Communication had never been so facilitated. So naturally, it went down in flames.</p>

<p><em>Boy meets girl, boy spends a magical time with girl, boy vanishes into thin air</em>. It was a tale as old as time, and Ben had no appetite for hounded game. What would happen if a boy met a boy in the one country on Earth that could win the Ghosting Olympics?</p>

<p>He didn’t. He entered a fancy Shinjuku skyscraper, where a Japanese goth whipped out a fat sashimi the likes of which he’d never seen at an onsen. But the toilet stall with the spaceship washlet was too cramped, the risk of being caught was too high, and the goth’s tongue was probing Ben’s tonsils. He’d never gone hunting in this country with such a heavy stick.</p>

<p>The entire situation was so uncomfortable, that he started to sweat. There was no way he could keep playing. And besides, size was secondary to beauty.</p>

<p>He apologized and left with the intention of never meeting the goth again. On his way home, he noticed the goth had blocked him.</p>

<h2 id="the-evolution-of-sex">The Evolution of Sex</h2>

<p>Ben woke groggy with jet lag and rushed to his first-day errands. In Japan, to rent an apartment, you needed a bank account. To open a bank account, you needed a phone number. To get a phone number, you needed to register your address. So the first step was to reside at a temporary accommodation.</p>

<p>He exited his share house in Shin Okubo. The main road was a Korean wet dream, full of Korean food, K-pop, and boy bands who strutted around just for the attention. It was also a pedestrian’s nightmare, with narrow pavements and hordes of slow walkers.</p>

<p>The air in Tokyo was heavy with humidity. It felt like a weight Ben couldn’t lift. The streets were grey and treeless, with noisy cars, quiet pedestrians, and tall buildings. People of all ages and genders were carrying parasols in the July heat. Some even used pocket fans.</p>

<p><em>Then again, ads inside trains in Tokyo featured Nintendo games more than any other product. Also, some anime.</em></p>

<p>Japanese people didn’t talk inside trains or eat while walking. No trash cans in public added a nuisance on the one hand, and eliminated all street trash on the other.</p>

<p>Instead, ubiquitous were actually the vending machines. And kimono-ed women. High school students with matching uniform, backpacks, and bowl cuts who wore masks as they chatted down empty alleys on their way back from school. And of course, a lot of attractive people who stood out among the swarms.</p>

<p>Whether foreigners of every stature, skin colour, and features, or people with outlandish outfits, there was no limit to the characters one could stumble upon simply by wandering in Tokyo.</p>

<p>Nor to the number of convenience stores. Ben discovered already on his first visit to one a new kimchi and fermented soybean sushi roll, plus a new matcha variant of his favourite Japanese snack.</p>

<p><em>Indeed, the best of both sexy worlds.</em></p>

<p>Japanese retail workers maintained utmost hygiene. They wore masks, received your money using a cash tray, and helped you with your smartphone using a pen with a soft end. That was how Ben bought his local SIM. Not a single customer service agent who assisted him in the busiest hub of the world’s biggest city spoke English.</p>

<p>Then a real estate agency for Japanese clients warned him that landlords refused foreigners, while a bank informed him that, to open an account, foreigners needed to reside in Japan for more than six months. The only possibility for fresh expats was the post office’s online banking system.</p>

<p>As Ben trotted across Shinjuku with his to-do list, he noticed how much Tokyo was loud. Vehicles vroomed, train announcements barked, jingles looped inside department stores, pedestrian crossings beeped, and phone cameras made shutter sounds. Only in residential streets did life turn quiet.</p>

<p>But it didn’t get any simpler. After wondering all his life how it felt to fall in love, lovemaking was his next big pursuit.</p>

<p>The first few times he had crept upon it, he hadn’t noticed it was close. Only in retrospect, in another land, had it dawned on him that he could have claimed the gold.</p>

<p>The last time was the best, because he’d recognized this uncharted territory while still in its zone. Yet it was over before even being set in motion.</p>

<p>Love always hit you out of left field. One day you felt powerful and potent, as if no one could get in your way. Then you stumbled upon a prowler who knocked you off your feet and splashed your guts on the road. You felt so safe with this new hunter, that you bared your soul. If your knees didn’t give in at first sight – if you didn’t feel awkward – if your intimacy didn’t spike all the way to wild proportions, then this race would crash down a waterfall.</p>

<p>When all of this had happened to Ben, the blood in his body had rushed to his heart. He’d forfeited the match, because too many thoughts had burst in his brain.</p>

<p>It was always the ones who towered above all. They were more attractive, more experienced, and he was a child who wanted to disappear off the face of the earth, rather than embarrass himself more.</p>

<p><em>What was it like to be in a relationship with someone you loved?</em> Ben wondered. <em>How did sex evolve with a reciprocal, emotional bond that transcended physical joys?</em></p>

<p><em>How would I answer those questions</em>. People talked the talk, but skipped the walk. They hounded you, lied to lure you in, and fled.</p>

<p>The cherry on the eggplant was: they always did so after planning a joint future. “<em>Next time we meet</em>…” “<em>If we got married, our names would sound like this</em>…” Worst was the simple promise: “<em>We’ll stay in touch</em>.”</p>

<p>Eligible women struggled to lay their hands on an eligible guy who would ditch the hunting grounds with them hand-in-hand. But what about guys who scoured rainbow brick roads? Ben couldn’t figure out if this game of hide-and-seek was a result of technological determinism, biological hormones, or gender roles. Were lesbians exempt from tagging along?</p>

<p>He knew neither guys who spurned hookup culture, nor girls who separated sex and emotion. Maybe the exceptions to this had never confided in him before.</p>

<p>The sun set as he returned to his share house through Tokyo’s red-light district, Kabukicho. The darkening sky and flashing neon; the hustle and bustle of diverse people. It felt both lonesome and grandiose.</p>

<p>He passed through his usual hotteok stand in Shin Okubo.</p>

<p>“Oh!” the Korean auntie gasped before he even said hello. Even with his hat on, she smiled at him in recognition, after a few times of him buying her pancakes in the fall.</p>

<p>“Where did you go?” she asked in Japanese. They exchanged a few sentences in Korean afterwards.</p>

<p>Ben rejoiced over the potential his new habitat held in store. Then he encountered a cockroach in his room even bigger than the huge ones back home.</p>

<h2 id="wheres-the-fire">Where’s the Fire?</h2>

<p>Saki came over in the evening. A bespectacled guy with a ponytail, there was no one in Japan Ben was closer to.</p>

<p>They hugged and immediately caught up over life and money. Sitting in Ben’s cramped room, with his suitcases open in complete disarray, Saki tried Ben’s fresh Israeli food.</p>

<p>“What have you been up to since we last met?” Ben asked. “Don’t say ‘just work.’”</p>

<p>“Just work,” he said.</p>

<p><em>Like any other Japanese person</em>.</p>

<p>But he would quit in the fall, and travel to meet his girlfriend in Spain.</p>

<p>Every dish Saki tried, he chewed without expressing any reaction. Then he voiced his opinion. The cheese reminded him of yogurt. Matza and taboon bread were curious. The best rugelach in the world, from a famous market in Jerusalem, were unbearably sweet. The most famous Israeli snack too.</p>

<p>Japanese people were infamous for being two-faced. They hid their private thoughts to maintain conformity. Saki stood out in his frankness. Yet his palate was still too Japanese for overseas levels of sweet.</p>

<p>In the Japanese language, the responsibility was the listener’s. They ought to understand everything through context, so the speaker omitted vital information. The closer people were, the better they understood one another. Thus, the less someone said, the better.</p>

<p>Customer service agents bombarded you with endless sentences rife with complicated words and grammar.</p>

<p>“<em>Welcomedearcustomerweareincrediblyindebtedtoyouforsteppingintoourestablishmentpleaseletusknowifyouneedanythingandhaveawonderfultime</em>” would be the closest equivalent in English to their speech.</p>

<p>In stark contrast to friendships in the West, Saki sprinkled short, casual sentences here and there.</p>

<p>Ben walked him outside after too short of a time together, and hugged him.</p>

<p>“Foreigners love to hug,” Saki chuckled.</p>

<p>At night, Ben tossed left and right in bed. His head was in Israel, but his body was in Japan. In the former, everything was big: reactions, hugs, everyday threats, and topics of discussion. In the latter, everything was small. Locals didn’t take up space, make noise, or boast about their achievements. They didn’t exhibit extreme emotions, fight over politics, or embrace at all. People bowed even when passing Ben, and constantly begged for good treatment. They never demanded it, like in Israel.</p>

<p>By midnight, Ben felt drained. It was hard to believe that this was still just his first full day. This organized wilderness required hunters to re-wire their brains. With no guarantee of a good job, an apartment, or a relationship, he lay wide awake on his thin mattress, heard his flatmates through the walls, and wondered: <em>was this the beginning of the rest of my life?</em></p>

<p>Chasing a prey was always more suspenseful than biting into its flesh. He just didn’t know if he’d get to taste anything that would match his palate.</p>

<p>He went to clear his head in the shower when he stumbled upon some flatmates in the hall. The English bodybuilder was walking around in his underwear, while the Turkish wrestler was trying to rest before his match tomorrow.</p>

<p>Soon enough, Ben huddled with three other flatmates in a tiny room, where two of them sat on a bed and two, like Japanese people, on the floor.</p>

<p>The two girls were both twentysomething bisexuals named Rose who had left their home country and stayed in the same room.</p>

<p>Rose Number One was a half Chinese and half North Indian who’d studied at an international school in Dubai. She had been traveling the world since high school graduation, with the goal of taking full advantage of her twenties. Asians rarely gave her the attention she was used to, because the locals here were more interested in white foreigners.</p>

<p>Rose Number Two was a Hungarian forensic investigator from a rough background who had dated a Japanese girl so shy, that she’d had no idea what to do in bed; and an ex-yakuza member who had fled to Europe. Nowadays, she spoke conversational Korean, and was dating a Korean pilot. He had already introduced her to his parents as his friend, yet barely initiated any sex.</p>

<p>“Next time you see him, tell him you want to take a rest,” Ben said. “Or, when you hold hands, stroke his palm with your thumb.”</p>

<p>After over a year together, she still had no idea how indirect most Asian were when it came to sex.</p>

<p>“I’ve never been introduced to someone’s parents,” Mateu muttered. He was a charismatic Catalan guy here for a summer course at a Japanese school before foreign exchange studies in Shanghai, because his Chinese was better.</p>

<p>Ben almost echoed his sentiment.</p>

<p>Mateu had just gone out on his first, awful date with someone from a dating app – a Chinese girl with a foot fetish who had tried to get freaky inside a karaoke parlour.</p>

<p>But he and Rose Number One were quickly churning out jokes. They possessed that quick sense of humour you had to rush to keep up with. Even though this foursome had just met, the two were already finishing each other’s quips, and smacking one another in hysterics.</p>

<p>“I’m so happy to hang out with cool people like you,” Mateu said.</p>

<p><em>Finally, back to an international, instant-friends, sexually-liberated vibe</em>. Throughout the day, the polite suppression of Japanese people had subdued Ben. <em>Where’s the fire?</em> He’d thought. Then he’d ignited it. For a warm social life in Tokyo, one ought to forage for Japanese and foreign wood.</p>

<p>After hours of late-night conversations, he retired to his room. From here on, he spent every night doomscrolling on social media in bed, searching for potential apartments, and waiting for his bloodshot eyes to close. Except they didn’t. He couldn’t stop talking to ex-lovers in his thoughts.</p>

<p>In the darkness, he munched on Israeli snacks, until birds chirped and light penetrated his window.</p>

<h2 id="the-straight-friend-zone">The Straight-Friend Zone</h2>

<p>After three hours of sleep, Ben woke even more exhausted. Orientation at his new school was a blur. He crashed on his bed in the afternoon and nearly dozed off, when Mateu suggested going to the Friday party at the Takadanobaba language café where Ben had volunteered before. It was always teeming with young people, both locals and tourists, who were hungry for some international relations. All-you-can-drink and refreshments were the hors d’oeuvres to the main course.</p>

<p>Then he found that his conversations with the partygoers didn’t flow as well as with his flatmates.</p>

<p>Guys and girls were hitting on each other in full force. Many a desirable bachelor and bachelorette were playing along. Ben kept to the sidelines, however, since there was no room here for any rainbow.</p>

<p>Then, after already talking to a few dozen people from all over the world since relocating to Tokyo, someone asked Ben for the first time about the Israeli-Gaza war.</p>

<p>The fact that it came from an American frat boy was no shock. The fact that he was half-Japanese and listened quietly to Ben’s opinion without arguing about politics reassured Ben that he had made it to the right side of the globe. Japan was a pocket reality where politics didn’t exist at all.</p>

<p>Across the room, Mateu was fidgeting with battle shock.</p>

<p>“I’m not good-looking enough to attract anyone’s attention,” he said.</p>

<p><em>False.</em></p>

<p>A Japanese girl fluent in Spanish had him gearing up for a crusade. She was probably the most beautiful Japanese person Ben had seen. After chatting with her, Mateu insisted that she wasn’t into him.</p>

<p>“How do you know for sure?” Ben asked. “Just go get her Instagram.”</p>

<p>“Nah, I’m only interested in those who are interested in me.”</p>

<p>Ben kept encouraging him throughout the night, the same way a straight Romanian guy had acted as his wingman during Seoul Pride a year ago. Mateu couldn’t even bear to try.</p>

<p>“I know how you feel,” Ben said. “Everyone has those nights. They’re kind of necessary, in a way.”</p>

<p>He mustered up the courage and danced with her. But her visible enjoyment wasn’t enough to change his mind.</p>

<p>Then Rose Number One mirrored Mateu’s mope.</p>

<p>The “hot guy” she’d been dating wanted to date other people. She seemed on the verge of tears.</p>

<p>“He’s in this room,” she muttered and looked away.</p>

<p>No girl at this party seemed cooler to Ben. She had straightened her wavy bangs, added a thin line of eyeliner on both sides of her eyes, pierced her nose, wore a metal chain, and showed off her flat stomach with an effortlessly cute punk outfit.  </p>

<p><em>Attractive straight people were also going through my average gay problems? Did everyone feel ugly and invisible at some point?</em></p>

<p>After the party, Ben noticed the only other queer in attendance: a thirtysomething billionaire who was working in fashion. He looked so familiar, that Ben could’ve sworn they’d met before.</p>

<p>He talked instead to a former graduate of his new school. Whether at the airport, at orientation, or at the café, every location in Tokyo ambushed him with a new, blue-eyed white guy who stood between 1.90 to 2 meters tall.</p>

<p>The straight-friend zone didn’t bother him, though. No heterosexual could make him nervous, nor reject him over his looks. He acted like one of their buddies, and that involved no deception.</p>

<h2 id="a-bittersweet-kiss">A Bittersweet Kiss</h2>

<p>Lunch with Saki at an Indonesian restaurant for his birthday. Shin Okubo, an immigrant neighbourhood, boasted a variety of cuisines.</p>

<p>“If you take out your wallet,” Ben said while ordering, “I will kill you.”</p>

<p>Saki let out a nervous laugh.</p>

<p>“I’m scared.”</p>

<p>He didn’t understand Ben’s humour at first. A Westerner would’ve retorted an even kinder intimidation.</p>

<p>Two 29-year-olds who shared the same passions, interests, and tastes. Lunch started off strangely awkward. Ben had already gotten used to rapid-fire English with his flatmates. Moreover, today was so hot, that both their faces were covered in sweat.</p>

<p>“You know, I’m also looking for a new apartment,” Saki said. “Do you wanna live together?”</p>

<p>“Absolutely not,” Ben said.</p>

<p>Saki laughed.</p>

<p>“I thought there weren’t any apartments for roommates in Japan,” Ben said. “Aren’t Japanese people too shy for that?”</p>

<p>“They dislike meeting new people,” Saki said.</p>

<p>After nearly choking on spicy Indonesian sauce, Ben walked Saki to the train station.</p>

<p>“I get that Japanese people don’t hug,” he said. “But what about birthdays?”</p>

<p>“Nope,” Saki said.</p>

<p>Ben rolled his eyes and waved goodbye as he paced away. Saki laughed and waved back.</p>

<p>The afternoon roared with a storm. Lightning flashed and thunder rumbled several times a minute. Ben rushed to Tokyo Station, the upscale (and sunny) business district.</p>

<p>_Taking a train in Tokyo was like entering a peaceful war zon_e. Automated voices announced instructions without stopping for air. Trains darted every two minutes, and passengers always filled them. The stairs were too populated to climb fast. Five-year-olds were roaming stations alone with a backpack bigger than them. Somehow, the whole experience was both orderly and clamorous.</p>

<p>Ben arrived at one of the fanciest museums he’d been to. It was the last day of a Brancusi exhibition that was free for students. He’d seen The Kiss, one of his favourite sculptures, twice or thrice before. It depicted two lovers locking bodies and lips. For the first time, Ben understood the full extent of the couple’s intimacy.</p>

<p>“<em>In love the paradox occurs that two beings become one and yet remain two</em>,” a Japanese guy from Kyoto had once quoted Erich Fromm to him.</p>

<p>The Kiss captured this unification in matter. The lovers were distinct, resembled each other in attributes, and were carved of a single stone.</p>

<p>Then a certain kiss resurfaced in Ben’s head. A long, breathless, first-person example of the above. He had recreated this sculpture without even realizing so.</p>

<p>“<em>I like how you hold me tight, even when you start to breathe heavily and snore</em>,” Ben recalled being told. “<em>It felt like I was being loved</em>.”</p>

<p>He continued around the exhibition with his jaw dropped. Geometrically simplified representations of birds and people gleamed like gold. Another exhibition featured every important Western artist from impressionism to abstract expressionism.</p>

<p>After the museum, he explored Ginza, Tokyo’s Fifth Avenue. It became a pedestrian zone on weekends, so shoppers could comfortably carry all their Gucci, Prada, and Hermes bags in the middle of the road.</p>

<p>As he savoured cherry blossom and salty lemon bread rolls from Japan’s oldest bakery, he asked questions as if to a void.</p>

<p><em>Have you ever made love? Did you catch that prey who dwarfed all? Did that lion also tame you, and with that arousing domestication, make you realize that this was freedom?</em></p>

<p>He walked back to Tokyo station. In the past, it had taken him half an hour to find the only shop in Japan outside Sendai that sold edamame shakes. It was his favourite local drink.</p>

<p>The person who had introduced him to it was the first queer Ben was interested in. Sendai was where their mutual pursuit had failed. He’d vowed to never return to that city. So he paced to the shop, remembering its exact location inside the transportational maze.</p>

<p>Nothing felt more refreshing at that moment than the thick, ice-cold smoothie, when every inch of his skin was covered in perspiration. Nor was there anything more bittersweet. The sugary soybeans brought memories to his taste buds and tears to his cheeks. He cried as he sipped while waiting for the train on the platform. For six months, he’d searched for that lost fairy.</p>

<p><em>Wanting someone who didn’t want you consumed you with defeat. Wanting someone who wanted you, and you rejected with cold feet, was your fault entirely.</em></p>

<p>He took the Yamanote line back to his share house. Twilight fell on the city. Tokyo felt too big at that moment. He would never find a lion in a jungle of forty million beasts.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/i4_We_kmuVc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="satbc" /><category term="ginza" /><category term="marunouchi" /><category term="shin-okubo" /><category term="takadanobaba" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Wait – have you ever been in love?” Sex and the City (season 1, episode 1)]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prologue</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/14/prologue-%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B0.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prologue" /><published>2024-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-07-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/14/prologue-%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B0</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/satbc/2024/07/14/prologue-%E3%83%97%E3%83%AD%E3%83%AD%E3%83%BC%E3%82%B0.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>And so we leave Carrie to enter a new phase in her life when she understands that she will have to find herself (without a man), and in doing so will hopefully be able to find a relationship.</p>

  <p>Candace Bushnell, “Sex and the City”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Sex and the City was my bible in high school. My conservative Jewish teacher taught me the Old Testament in class, while four single women taught me debauchery at night.</p>

<p>Together with The L Word, those women turned me straight. But for ten years, I never really understood them, until I fell in love.</p>

<p>It’s time for a re-watch.</p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/image-3.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://m.media-amazon.com/images/M/MV5BNDgyODk4MTktODE3YS00YTUzLTlmYTgtOGJmZjMzZGM5NDBlXkEyXkFqcGdeQXVyOTA3MTMyOTk@._V1_FMjpg_UX1000_.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Carrie Bradshaw, the main character of Sex and the City, wrote a weekly column about sex and relationships as a straight female in Manhattan in the late 1990’s. I will do the same as a queer male in Tokyo in the mid-2020’s. Every week, I’ll watch an episode of these TV shows, and explore people the way they did.</p>

<p>After a three-month hiatus from dating in Israel, I’m going back to those Tokyo nights that kept me wide awake.</p>

<p><a href="https://kesem.co.uk/lessons-from-running-a-blog-%d7%9c%d7%a7%d7%97%d7%99%d7%9d-%d7%9e%d7%a0%d7%99%d7%94%d7%95%d7%9c-%d7%99%d7%95%d7%9e%d7%9f-%d7%a8%d7%a9%d7%aa/">Since blogging about my dating life already ruined my dating life</a>, this time the story will follow a different character. Some of the anecdotes will be inspired from my life, and some from others’ (with their permission).</p>

<p>It’s funny that I’m following Carrie’s four-hundred-dollar-strappy-sandal footsteps. When Sex and the City premiered, my mom looked so much like the main character, that some people still call her Sarah Jessica to this day (after the actress who played Carrie).</p>

<p>But this new project won’t be easy. Between attending school every day, studying Japanese, Korean, and Chinese in the afternoon, apartment-hunting, job-hunting, cooking, keeping in touch with friends and family, dating, going out every weekend, and getting enough sleep, running a weekly blog might be too ambitious. No, I haven’t surrendered to the failures of my travel journal – but this time, I’ll try to keep chapters brief. I wish my phone could detect doom-scrolling on social media and remind me to not waste my life. I wish I could also squeeze into this schedule playing my Nintendo Switch.</p>

<p>I’ve just moved into my temporary share house. Apart from a towel, I own nothing at all. With books sprawled on my bed, a laptop on a pillow, empty takeout, and industrial ice cream, I am taking a page out of Candace Bushnell’s book – literally, since she wrote Sex and the City. Her anthology, Shakespeare’s sonnets, Virginia Woolf’s diary, and Alice Munro’s Too Much Happiness (a collection of short stories about the mortality of intimacy that changed my life) will guide me through the bizarre realm of love.</p>

<figure>

![](https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/image-1.png)

![](https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/image.png)

<figcaption>

Sex and the City (season 1 episode 1)

</figcaption>

</figure>

<p>Asians would put me in quarantine if they knew I’m bringing all these germs to bed. But at least my futon is clean of the germs that matter.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/T692utQOQvI" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="satbc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[And so we leave Carrie to enter a new phase in her life when she understands that she will have to find herself (without a man), and in doing so will hopefully be able to find a relationship. Candace Bushnell, “Sex and the City”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Israel, Synopsis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/israel/2024/06/30/israel-synopsis-%D7%99%D7%A9%D7%A8%D7%90%D7%9C-%D7%AA%D7%A7%D7%A6%D7%99%D7%A8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Israel, Synopsis" /><published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/israel/2024/06/30/israel-synopsis-%D7%99%D7%A9%D7%A8%D7%90%D7%9C-%D7%AA%D7%A7%D7%A6%D7%99%D7%A8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/israel/2024/06/30/israel-synopsis-%D7%99%D7%A9%D7%A8%D7%90%D7%9C-%D7%AA%D7%A7%D7%A6%D7%99%D7%A8.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="synopsis">Synopsis</h2>

<p>In April 2024, after fourteen months of travelling the Far East, I returned to my country of origin in the Middle East. Apart from the food, I hadn’t missed a single thing (“<a href="/israel/2024/04/22/the-holy-land-%D7%90%D7%A8%D7%A5-%D7%94%D7%A7%D7%95%D7%93%D7%A9.html">The Holy Land / ארץ הקודש</a>”).</p>

<p>Already on my first day, I came out to my mom, who asked me to keep my sexuality secret. Moreover, I discovered that unrequited love had scarred my body for life.</p>

<p>Despite spending nearly all my years here, I’d grown so used to Asian cultures, that every small thing in Israel shocked and vexed me. Constant criticism, pressure, and arguments from every person around me – whether friends, strangers, or family – added fuel to the fire ignited by the ongoing war, the worst in Israeli history.</p>

<p>After two weeks of uncontrollable longing, I began to re-adjust to this country. I realized that all my relationships were asymmetrical, and that I’d lost the love in my life (“<a href="/israel/2024/05/21/the-ghost-writer-part-1-%D7%A1%D7%95%D7%A4%D7%A8-%D7%94%D7%A6%D7%9C%D7%9C%D7%99%D7%9D-%D7%97%D7%9C%D7%A7-%D7%90.html">The Ghost Writer, Part 1 / סופר הצללים, חלק א’</a>”).</p>

<p>Yet the more I understood the ups and downs of love, the less it emotional it made me. Just like in middle school, I grew lonely, misunderstood, angry, haunted by nightmares, and unable to shed tears. I hated people for breaking their promises to me or for fighting, and decided that I no longer wished to love. I grew apart from my overbearing family and fell out of love, but also appreciated my belonging to a minority (“<a href="/israel/2024/06/07/the-ghost-writer-part-2-%D7%A1%D7%95%D7%A4%D7%A8-%D7%94%D7%A6%D7%9C%D7%9C%D7%99%D7%9D-%D7%97%D7%9C%D7%A7-%D7%91.html" title="The Ghost Writer, Part 2 / סופר הצללים, חלק ב’">The Ghost Writer, Part 2 / סופר הצללים, חלק ב</a>’”).</p>

<p>Only my trauma from middle school brought back tears. I attended the disappointing Tel Aviv Pride, reconnected with childhood friends, and finally got over my romantic obsession. I rejoiced over the relief that came with moving on, grew close to my family, and re-assimilated into Israel.</p>

<p>My trip and everyone from it seemed ages ago. I dipped my toes into the local dating scene, and began to appreciate certain aspects of Israel. Right when I started to feel good about my life here, though, it was time for farewell. I cried on my last day with my loved ones (“<a href="/israel/2024/06/28/the-ghost-writer-part-3-%D7%A1%D7%95%D7%A4%D7%A8-%D7%94%D7%A6%D7%9C%D7%9C%D7%99%D7%9D-%D7%97%D7%9C%D7%A7-%D7%92.html">The Ghost Writer, Part 3 / סופר הצללים, חלק ג’</a>”).</p>

<p>Three months in my most hated place on Earth ended up surprisingly cleansing. I relocated to Japan as a tougher, more mature person, who was no longer emotionally crippled by love (“<a href="/israel/poems/2024/06/29/shalom-%D7%A9%D7%9C%D7%95%D7%9D.html">Shalom / שלום</a>”).</p>

<h2 id="all-israel-posts">All “Israel” Posts</h2>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="israel" /><category term="synopsis" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Synopsis]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Resident of Japan</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/06/30/a-resident-of-japan-%E6%97%A5%E6%9C%AC%E3%81%AE%E5%9C%A8%E7%95%99%E8%80%85.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Resident of Japan" /><published>2024-06-30T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-30T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/06/30/a-resident-of-japan-%E6%97%A5%E6%9C%AC%E3%81%AE%E5%9C%A8%E7%95%99%E8%80%85</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/a-resident-of-japan/2024/06/30/a-resident-of-japan-%E6%97%A5%E6%9C%AC%E3%81%AE%E5%9C%A8%E7%95%99%E8%80%85.html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
  <p>As the years go by, the land far away from home will be inhabited like our own land. As days go by, the village we settle down in will be our hometown.</p>

  <p>Chun Shen Jun, “Bidding Farewell to My Son”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After nine months last year as a tourist, I’m back in Japan – and this time, I have a residence card.</p>

<p>Today has been in the making since I started learning Japanese when I was twelve. Growing up in an Israeli suburb and relocating at twenty-four to a medieval town in England for my second alma mater, I’ve always spurned urbanism. Now, I picked the biggest city in the world, where I’ll live within walking distance to the world’s busiest train station.</p>

<p>I’ve stayed in Tokyo three times as a tourist, for a total of seven weeks. I’ll never forget my first day here: 18 April 2023, arriving in Shinjuku on a long-distance bus from Matsumoto, after travelling all over Japan for two and a half months. I’d kept Tokyo as my last stop in this country.</p>

<p>When I left the countryside and got off at the world’s busiest transport hub at night, I immediately called my sister.</p>

<p>“I feel like Anne Hathaway in The Devil Wears Prada,” I gushed with my mouth agape in disbelief. “On her first night in Paris.”</p>

<p>Even my first night in Paris hadn’t dazzled me as much.</p>

<p>Since then, my weeks in the world’s most populated city – with the most opportunities, and the most friends I’d made – were marred by a shrinking budget and escalating alienation. I found myself not knowing where to spend the night, and felt like I had no one to count on.</p>

<p>Now that I’ll live in Tokyo in my own apartment, will I be able to build a more robust social circle? Will my dating life finally grow stable?</p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360577/website_images/2024/07/img_0155-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/img_0156-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360580/website_images/2024/07/img_0164-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://kesem.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/img_0163-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360578/website_images/2024/07/img_0169-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="https://res.cloudinary.com/det9qfsir/image/upload/v1769360581/website_images/2024/07/img_0175-2-768x1024.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>The next few weeks will be hectic. School every day, apartment hunting, job hunting, legal errands to complete my relocation, treasure hunting for second-hand furniture: writing should be the last activity in my head. So, naturally, I decided to overhaul this blog, and start a new chapter.</p>

<p>Once I settle in and do all this, I’ll spend my weekdays at school and my weekends at the club, because that’s what your twenties are for. I already know the latter will involve a lot of rejection. That’s what society is for.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/X9YMU0WeBwU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="a-resident-of-japan" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the years go by, the land far away from home will be inhabited like our own land. As days go by, the village we settle down in will be our hometown. Chun Shen Jun, “Bidding Farewell to My Son”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Shalom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/israel/poems/2024/06/29/shalom-%D7%A9%D7%9C%D7%95%D7%9D.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Shalom" /><published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/israel/poems/2024/06/29/shalom-%D7%A9%D7%9C%D7%95%D7%9D</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/israel/poems/2024/06/29/shalom-%D7%A9%D7%9C%D7%95%D7%9D.html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three months have come to a close <br />
This time in my home country  <br />
When it is ravaged by war <br />
Israel felt like Mars when I landed  <br />
Since then, I learned how to handle its residents <br />
I’m more blunt and less meek now <br />
I love this field that I plough <br />
 <br />
Arguments in this hot climate were daily <br />
Until love healed my farmer’s lung <br />
For the first time, I’ll miss my friends and family <br />
No outsider will ever understand our reality <br />
We share more than a tongue <br />
 <br />
The cherry on the hummus was finally overcoming  <br />
Every romance from my trip that ended in woes <br />
Falling out of love feels better than falling in love <br />
It set me free. I don’t need you <br />
I am back behind the wheel of my train of thought <br />
 <br />
When I recall moments where you gave me life <br />
I feel dead <br />
When I think how, in vain, I love <br />
I hate <br />
How can a flower bloom in gloom? <br />
How can one country thunder with booms  <br />
 <br />
I hate how you charged at me and then fled <br />
I hate how you held your cards close to your chest <br />
I hate how you acted so gentle and polite <br />
I hate how you soothed me like evening light <br />
I hate your black hole eyes and infinite grin <br />
I hate your sharp bones and perfect skin <br />
I hate your style and impeccable taste <br />
I hate how you lied straight to my face <br />
I hate how your hobbies darkened your profession <br />
I hate what your habitat told about your transgression <br />
I hate your voice and mishmash of an accent <br />
I hate studying your first language <br />
I hate how no one in the room mattered when you were in it   <br />
I hate how, to avoid murk, you left beaming <br />
I hate your soft kisses and tight embrace <br />
I hate how our lips aligned in size and shape  <br />
I hate how your body overshadowed mine  <br />
I hate how you had it all figured out <br />
 <br />
Worst of all, I hate how I could never hate you <br />
Even if reason pushed all to convince me to <br />
I could never, do you hear me? <br />
You don’t <br />
Not in a million years, not a little, not at all <br />
 <br />
How can one lightning flash <br />
Rumble for eternity? <br />
I never needed you to survive <br />
But I craved you to feel alive <br />
I hope that somewhere on this planet, you’re well <br />
Please laugh more than I fret <br />
I would crumble if something crushed you <br />
But you already moved on to someone better <br />
 <br />
Thank you for the lust and the rust <br />
And the dust you paid when you broke the trust <br />
I’m a better person because of your defects  <br />
I matured when you raised me <br />
By ditching all respects <br />
You never admit when you’re wrong <br />
Never apologize and confront like an adult <br />
You’d rather declare things you never meant <br />
I know what mistakes not to make <br />
 <br />
Never text a writer; their stories have no end <br />
Never charm a novelist; they analyse you like a character <br />
Never climax a dramatist; they always have a speech at hand <br />
Never slam a poet; they won’t spare you the taint of their pen <br />
Never lie to a wordsmith; they won’t forget what you said <br />
Never fabulate an author; you’ll read about your actions someday <br />
 <br />
This isn’t the first chapter <br />
And it won’t be the last <br />
I can stride with a broken leg <br />
I’ll donate blood with a wounded heart  <br />
I’ll smile because I’ve lost the ability to cry <br />
I’ll live like a bacchanal because I want to die <br />
 <br />
I wince when the gaffes I’ve made with you pop in my mind <br />
Who was that wimp? <br />
I don’t recognize him now <br />
Yet this doesn’t haunt me anymore <br />
I’m not the kid you tossed like a toy <br />
 <br />
So I’ll never write about you again <br />
Thousands of words you never read <br />
I never got to say I love you <br />
And I’ll never feel it again <br />
Shalom to Israel, shalom to love <br />
 <br />
Farewell</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="israel" /><category term="poems" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Another three months have come to a close  This time in my home country   When it is ravaged by war  Israel felt like Mars when I landed   Since then, I learned how to handle its residents  I’m more blunt and less meek now  I love this field that I plough    Arguments in this hot climate were daily  Until love healed my farmer’s lung  For the first time, I’ll miss my friends and family  No outsider will ever understand our reality  We share more than a tongue    The cherry on the hummus was finally overcoming   Every romance from my trip that ended in woes  Falling out of love feels better than falling in love  It set me free. I don’t need you  I am back behind the wheel of my train of thought    When I recall moments where you gave me life  I feel dead  When I think how, in vain, I love  I hate  How can a flower bloom in gloom?  How can one country thunder with booms     I hate how you charged at me and then fled  I hate how you held your cards close to your chest  I hate how you acted so gentle and polite  I hate how you soothed me like evening light  I hate your black hole eyes and infinite grin  I hate your sharp bones and perfect skin  I hate your style and impeccable taste  I hate how you lied straight to my face  I hate how your hobbies darkened your profession  I hate what your habitat told about your transgression  I hate your voice and mishmash of an accent  I hate studying your first language  I hate how no one in the room mattered when you were in it    I hate how, to avoid murk, you left beaming  I hate your soft kisses and tight embrace  I hate how our lips aligned in size and shape   I hate how your body overshadowed mine   I hate how you had it all figured out    Worst of all, I hate how I could never hate you  Even if reason pushed all to convince me to  I could never, do you hear me?  You don’t  Not in a million years, not a little, not at all    How can one lightning flash  Rumble for eternity?  I never needed you to survive  But I craved you to feel alive  I hope that somewhere on this planet, you’re well  Please laugh more than I fret  I would crumble if something crushed you  But you already moved on to someone better    Thank you for the lust and the rust  And the dust you paid when you broke the trust  I’m a better person because of your defects   I matured when you raised me  By ditching all respects  You never admit when you’re wrong  Never apologize and confront like an adult  You’d rather declare things you never meant  I know what mistakes not to make    Never text a writer; their stories have no end  Never charm a novelist; they analyse you like a character  Never climax a dramatist; they always have a speech at hand  Never slam a poet; they won’t spare you the taint of their pen  Never lie to a wordsmith; they won’t forget what you said  Never fabulate an author; you’ll read about your actions someday    This isn’t the first chapter  And it won’t be the last  I can stride with a broken leg  I’ll donate blood with a wounded heart   I’ll smile because I’ve lost the ability to cry  I’ll live like a bacchanal because I want to die    I wince when the gaffes I’ve made with you pop in my mind  Who was that wimp?  I don’t recognize him now  Yet this doesn’t haunt me anymore  I’m not the kid you tossed like a toy    So I’ll never write about you again  Thousands of words you never read  I never got to say I love you  And I’ll never feel it again  Shalom to Israel, shalom to love    Farewell]]></summary></entry></feed>